<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>News &amp; Press</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/default.asp</link>
<description><![CDATA[  Read about recent events, essential information and the latest community news.  ]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 17:49:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 14:20:53 GMT</pubDate>
<copyright>Copyright &#xA9; 2020 Licensing Executives Society (LES)</copyright>
<atom:link href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news_rss.asp?cat=10999" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
<item>
<title>Licensing Executives Society Announces Distinguished Board of Directors  for 2020-2021 Term</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=531802</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=531802</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p align="center" style="background: white; text-align: center;"><i><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Diverse Group of Intellectual Property and Licensing Leaders Representing<br> Organizations of All Sizes and Types Join Board </span></i></p> <p style="background: white;"><b><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">RESTON, Va.</span></b><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">&nbsp;– Oct. 20, 2020 --</span><span style="color: black;"><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/"><span style="color: rgb(44, 170, 0); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES)</span></a></span><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">&nbsp;has elected new members to its </span><span style="color: black;"><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/board-of-directors/"><span style="color: rgb(44, 170, 0); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Board of Directors</span></a></span><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">&nbsp;for 2020-2021. The additions extend the organization's broad </span><span style="color: rgb(127, 127, 127); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">leadership representation from the IP and licensing industry, ensuring that LES continues to engage and empower those involved in LES' intellectual property (IP) and standards communities while progressing toward its goals.</span></p> <p><span style="color: rgb(127, 127, 127); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">“Welcome to the new LES Board of Directors, a talented and diverse group of high character and motivated&nbsp;individuals with strong leadership skills and a vast array of experience in advancing the business of intellectual property. Their proven acumen will further allow LES to strategically move forward in delivering value to our membership, pursuing our key initiatives, and otherwise improving our membership experience and enhancing the brand of LES,” said outgoing LES President and Chair&nbsp;Gary Fedorochko.</span></p> <p style="background: white;"><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">As part of the Executive Committee's seamless leadership transition,&nbsp;</span><span style="color: rgb(127, 127, 127); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">Gillian Fenton, previously LES' president-elect, moves into the role of president and chair of LES. Director&nbsp;Scott Williams&nbsp;has been named president- and chair-elect, and&nbsp;Rachel Kreppel&nbsp;is continuing her role as c</span><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">ounsel to the board.</span></p> <p style="background: white;"><span style="color: rgb(127, 127, 127); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">"I'm grateful for this opportunity to serve LES as this year’s Board Chair, and&nbsp;to enhance LES’ value to our members. I am committed to leading strategic and cultural changes to advance the LES vision and mission and<b><i> </i></b>lead the Society through the pandemic and associated economic sea change throughout the coming year," said Fenton. "On behalf of the Board, I would like to thank Gary Fedorochko for his dedicated service to LES during his term as President and Chair. Gary’s commitment and<b><i> </i></b>agile leadership has<b><i> </i></b>inspired me to envision a bright future for LES.”</span></p> <p style="background: white;"><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">The full roster is available on the&nbsp;</span><span style="color: black;"><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/board-of-directors/"><span style="color: rgb(44, 170, 0); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">LES website</span></a></span><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">.</span></p> <p style="background: white;"><b><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">2020-2021 Officers </span></b></p> <p style="background: white;"><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">President and Chair of the Board – Gillian Fenton<br> President-Elect and Chair-Elect of the Board – Scott Williams<br> Immediate Past-President and Past-Chair of the Board - Gary Fedorochko<br> Secretary – Kevin Spivak<br> Treasurer – Michele Riley<br> Counsel – Rachel Kreppel</span></p> <p style="background: white;"><b><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">New 2020-2021 Directors</span></b><span style="color: rgb(121, 123, 125); font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"><br> Julie Barnes-Weise<br> Vincent Bergeron<br> Mihaela Bojin<br> Michael Perham</span></p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px 0px 10px; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);"><span style="box-sizing: border-box; font-weight: 700;">About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</span></p><p style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px 0px 10px; background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);">For over 50 years, the Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) has been the leading association for intellectual property (IP), technology, and business development professionals. The Society brings IP and licensing groups together to network, collaborate, and discuss some of the most critical issues facing the industry today and tomorrow. The LES community drives strategy, transactions, and deals involving intellectual property, business, and law, to fuel the evolving innovation economy. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 8,000 members in 90 countries.&nbsp;<a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/" style="box-sizing: border-box; background-color: transparent; text-decoration-line: none;">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 15:20:53 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Licensing Executives Society to Honor 2020 Award Recipients at Annual Meeting</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=530807</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=530807</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><i>For Outstanding Achievements in the Field of Licensing, LES to Honor Deals of Distinction, Frank Barnes Mentor and Presidential Award Winners</i></p>
<p>RESTON, Va. – October 16, 2020 – The <a href="about:blank">Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) (LES)</a> is pleased to announce that the Society will present its 2020 Awards for outstanding achievements and service at its <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/am20/agenda/">Annual Meeting</a>.
    LES will present the annual <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/page/dda">Deals of Distinction™ Awards</a> and the <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/page/FrankBarnesAward">Frank Barnes Mentor Award</a> on Friday, October 16, from 3:00
    to 4:00 p.m. LES will present the Presidential Award on Monday, October 19, from 2:00 to 3:00 p.m. Registration and conference information are available at <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/am20/">https://lesmeetings.org/am20/</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Four Companies Honored with Deals of Distinction™ Awards</strong></p>
<p>LES President and Chair Gary Fedorochko will recognize the 2020 LES <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/page/dda">Deals of Distinction™ Awards</a> recipients. The 2020 recipients are four companies that orchestrated the year’s most outstanding licensing
    and business deals in four key sectors and include:</p>
<ul>
    <li>Chemicals, Energy, Environment & Materials Sector: ExxonMobil Upstream Research Company and The University of Houston – <em>Low-Frequency Seismic Technology License and Consortium Foundational Agreement</em>
    </li>
    <li>High Technology Sector: University of Chicago, Configuration Dynamics and Underwriter Laboratories for their Software Technology Commercialization deal
    </li>
    <li>Industry-University-Government Interface Sector: Oregon Health & Science University and Illumina – <em>Single-Cell Genome Sequencing Processes and Tools License</em>
    </li>
    <li>Life Sciences Sector: Sangamo Therapeutics and Biogen -- <em>A broad global R&D collaboration for gene regulation therapies to treat neurological diseases</em>
    </li>
</ul>

<p>“Through well-organized commercialization of intellectual property, we can drive growth across all business sectors in our global economy, from traditional business products to emerging product technologies. The 2020 award winners through creative licensing
    deals allow the potential of exciting and powerful innovations to be commercially realized, and we are pleased to recognize their success,” said Fedorochko. “Our thanks go to the Awards Committee for highlighting the continued achievements of LES
    members.”
</p>
<p><strong>Steven M. Ferguson Named 2020 LES Frank Barnes Mentor Award Recipient</strong></p>
<p>LES Awards Committee Chair Don Drinkwater will present Steven M. Ferguson, CLP, Special Advisor at NIH’s Office of Technology Transfer, with the 2020 LES <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/page/FrankBarnesAward">Frank Barnes Mentor Award</a>. Like
    Mr. Barnes, Ferguson has devoted his career to inspiring and encouraging further innovation in the licensing sector and is a mentor for the broader technology transfer community.</p>
<p>“Steve’s service to LES has been truly admirable. He is an expert, a socially-aware leader, and an educator. In his nearly 30-year career in technology transfer, he has trained and mentored dozens and dozens of licensing professionals,” said Fedorochko.
    “He continues to be a leading light to all technology transfer professionals, always gracious and generous in sharing his knowledge and enthusiasm about the field. Congratulations to Steve from the entire LES community.”</p>

<p><strong>Bill Elkington Honored with 2020 LES Presidential Award</strong></p>
<p>For his driving energy around Intellectual Capital Management (ICM) and his championing of the LES Standards Initiative since its inception, Bill Elkington, Mind IC managing member, LES past president, and past LES Standards chair, will be presented with
    the LES Presidential Award. As the highest honor that LES can give to a community member, the award recognizes Elkington for his outstanding contribution to the Society’s health, vibrancy, and well-being.</p>
<p>“Bill’s passion and warm personality, in addition to his sharp intellect, make him an immutable force when it comes to ICM and standards of excellence,” said Drinkwater. “His launch of the LES Standards program has transformed the organization, resulting
    in an ANSI-accredited program with eight active standards committees. Bill has a deep understanding of the business of licensing and ICM, through which he has served our profession faithfully for decades by his leadership and strength of character.
    We, as a profession, are better because of Bill.”</p>

<p><strong>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</strong></p>
<p>For over 50 years, the Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) has been the leading association for intellectual property (IP), technology, and business development professionals. The Society brings IP and licensing groups together
    to network, collaborate, and discuss some of the most critical issues facing the industry today and tomorrow. The LES community drives strategy, transactions, and deals involving intellectual property, business, and law, to fuel the evolving innovation
    economy. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 8,000 members in 90 countries. <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES Standards Committee Initiates Public Review of New Standard</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=494784</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=494784</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h2 style="text-align: center;">Licensing Executives Society  Standards Committee Initiates Public Review of New Standard for Protecting  Intellectual Property in the Global Supply Chain</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Manufacturers and Other Global  Supply Chain Stakeholders Encouraged to Review and Comment on Standard</em>&nbsp; </p>
<p><strong>RESTON, Va.</strong> – March  30, 2020 -- <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/?_zs=iLSCa&amp;_zl=rD422" target="_blank"><strong>The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and  Canada), Inc.</strong></a> (LES) today announced the start of a 60-day  public review period for the LES draft standard <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/Standards-Review" target="_blank"><strong>"Protecting Intellectual Property (IP) in the Global Supply  Chain."</strong></a> This formal call for comment is made by the American National  Standards Institute (ANSI), as published in the March 27th edition of the <a href="https://share.ansi.org/Shared%20Documents/Standards%20Action/2020-PDFs/SAV5113.pdf">ANSI  Standards Action</a>. Stakeholders are invited to comment on the standard through the  public review period, which expires May 26, 2020. Stakeholders and the public  at large can review the standard and provide comments by visiting <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/Standards-Review" target="_blank">https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/Standards-Review<strong>.</strong></a><br />
&nbsp; <br />
Developed by the <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards?_zs=iLSCa&amp;_zl=sD422" target="_blank"><strong>LES IP Protection in Supply Chain Standards  Committee</strong></a>, the draft standard defines a common set of expectations for  what companies can and should do to protect their own IP and the IP of  customers, suppliers, and partners. The Committee's vision is to develop  voluntary consensus standards for business processes requiring the disclosure  and sharing of IP throughout the supply chain, from concept through finished  product. It represents a consensus of a diverse collection of stakeholders in  supply chain manufacturing. The standard is not intended to replace legal and  contractual IP protection methods, but instead to supplement them by establishing  performance standards for an IP protection management system and business  processes designed to protect all types of IP in the global supply chain.<br />
&nbsp; <br />
As an ANSI-Accredited Standards  Developer, LES encourages IP thought leaders everywhere to participate in the  development and review of these voluntary consensus standards for IP management  practices that are fair, effective, and prudent. The LES Standards Initiative  encourages IP and supply chain thought leaders around the globe to <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards?_zs=iLSCa&amp;_zl=sD422" target="_blank"><strong>participate in the public review of the LES  draft standard.</strong></a></p>
<p>"The LES IP Protection in  Supply Chain draft standard provides guidelines for fostering a stronger  culture of IP protection throughout the supply chain," said LES President and  Chair of the Board Gary Fedorochko. "The draft standard will help companies  understand that filing patents, registering trademarks, and relying on  contracts are not enough to protect IP in today's global economy. We hope that  ultimately the standard will help companies gain a competitive advantage by  demonstrating that they have a commitment to protect IP -- and that they are  doing something about it."<br />
&nbsp; <br />
<a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards" target="_blank"><strong>The LES IP Protection in Supply Chain Standards Committee</strong></a> is led  by subject matter experts from organizations across the supply chain industry,  including operating companies, academia, consulting firms, and law firms. The  standard provides a consensus view of effective practices in areas such as: IP  policies and procedures; risk assessment; third-party management; information  technology and physical security; monitoring and corrective actions; training  and awareness building; and senior management commitment.<br />
&nbsp; <br />
"The LES IP Protection in Supply  Chain draft standard is one of the first to address protection for intellectual  property in the supply chain," said LES IP Protection in Supply Chain Standards  Committee Chair Craig Moss. "Our goal is to create shared expectations for the  elements of an IP protection management system and to enable any company to  show that it has the business processes in place to protect its own IP and the  IP of third parties -- customers, suppliers, distributors, joint venture  partners, and anyone else involved. In today's digital world, protecting IP is  critical to all companies regardless of their location and position in the  supply chain."<br />
&nbsp; <br />
<strong>Join the LES Standards  Initiative</strong> <br />
To become a member of the LES  Standards Initiative, and any of its working committees, including the LES IP  Protection in Supply Chain Committee, visit <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards?_zs=iLSCa&amp;_zl=sD422" target="_blank"><strong>https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards.</strong></a> Participation in the LES Standards Initiative affords enterprises and  individuals the opportunity to participate in the creation of consensus-based,  voluntary standards for IP management, and to learn first-hand from peers about  IP practices developed and deployed throughout the innovation ecosystem. <br />
&nbsp; <br />
<strong>About the Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</strong><br />
Established in 1965, the  Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional  society of 2,500 members engaged in the creation, commercial development and  orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of  intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards development.  LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model innovators,  consultants, dealmakers, economists, engineers, IP valuation experts, lawyers,  licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition experts, public policy  leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain managers, tax  specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members represent  innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds — such as government  laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating companies,  regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms and trade associations. LES  is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc.  (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 8,000 members in 90 countries. <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/?_zs=iLSCa&amp;_zl=rD422" target="_blank"><strong>www.lesusacanada.org</strong></a>.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Licensing Executive Society Names Jeffrey S. Whittle the Frank Barnes Mentor Award Recipient</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=474491</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=474491</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><em><u>For more information:</u></em><br />
Jessie Hennion<br />
LES PR Director<br />
jhennion@virtualinc.com<br />
+1 781-876-6280<br />
<br />
<u>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</u><strong> </strong></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Licensing Executive Society  Names Jeffrey S. Whittle the Frank Barnes Mentor Award Recipient</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>For His  Outstanding Work as Mentor in the Field of Licensing, Whittle Will Be Honored  During the Society’s Annual Meeting Award Ceremony, October 22, in Phoenix</em></p>
<p><strong>RESTON, Va. – </strong>Oct. 22, 2019 -- The <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada)</a><u> (LES)</u> today announced that it has  selected intellectual property (IP) attorney <a href="https://www.womblebonddickinson.com/us/people/jeffrey-s-whittle">Jeffrey S. Whittle</a>, LES past president and a  former member of the LES Board of Directors, as the recipient of the <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/FrankBarnesAward">2019 LES Frank Barnes Mentor Award</a>. Whittle is  the managing partner of Womble Bond Dickinson’s Houston office and a co-lead of  the law firm’s Energy Sector team. His longtime mentorship activities in the  field of licensing have qualified him for one of the highest honors that LES  can give to a member of the licensing community. He joins a long and <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/FrankBarnesAward">distinguished line of winners</a> who, like Frank  Barnes himself, advanced the LES mission by generously sharing their time and  talents to support their colleagues.</p>
<p> Established  in 2000 by LES to memorialize Barnes' contributions to the field of licensing,  the award is presented annually to one LES member who has dedicated  considerable time and energy to mentoring fellow licensing professionals. Whittle will be honored at the<a href="https://lesmeetings.org/">LES Annual Meeting Frank Barnes Award Celebration</a> held during today’s Keynote  Speaker Luncheon with Microsoft for Startups Managing Director Shaloo Garg,  from Noon to 1:45 p.m., at the<a href="https://lesmeetings.org/venue/">JW Marriott Desert  Ridge Resort & Spa</a>. All attendees are welcome.</p>
<p> "This year by wide acclaim, the  award selection committee is pleased to present Jeffrey with the 2019 LES Frank  Barnes Mentor Award. Jeffrey is a natural mentor and has devoted his entire  career to inspire and encourage further innovation in the licensing sector.  Additionally, Jeffrey has always been a trusted advisor and mentor for our  community," said Don Drinkwater, chair of the Frank Barnes Award  Committee, former LES Board of Directors member and past president of the LES  Foundation. "In addition to  embodying many of Frank Barnes' estimable mentor qualities, his service to LES  has been truly admirable. Congratulations to Jeffrey from the whole  organization."</p>
<p>  Whittle  is a past president and chair of LES (2015-2016), and he served on the LES  Board for over seven years. He is currently Co-Chair of the Americas Committee  for Licensing Executives Society International (LESI). He was named 2018 Global  IP Attorney of the Year by <em>Legal Era</em> and received the 2015 Distinguished Service Award from the University of  Houston Law Center. A Certified Licensing Professional, he is a frequent and  highly sought-after speaker and author, nationally and internationally, on  various intellectual property, licensing, and technology topics.</p>
<p>Whittle’s  IP practice serves U.S. and international clients in the energy and high-tech  industries. He advises on strategic and complex technology transactions,  licensing, patent protection, portfolio analysis, and other contentious and  transactional intellectual property matters including <em>inter partes</em> reexaminations, post-grant reviews and derivation  proceedings, among other disputed cases.</p>
<p><strong>About Licensing Executives  Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</strong><br />
Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a  professional society of 2,500 members engaged in the creation, commercial development and orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model innovators, consultants, dealmakers, economists, engineers, IP valuation experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds -- such as government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms and trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society  International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 8,000  members in 90 countries. For more information about LES, go to <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <strong>###</strong></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title> Licensing Executives Society Announces Distinguished Board of Directors for 2019-2020 Term</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=474490</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=474490</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><em><u>For more information:</u></em><br />
Jessie Hennion<br />
LES PR Director<br />
jhennion@virtualinc.com<br />
+1 781-876-6280</p>
<p><u>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</u><u> </u></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong style="text-align: center;">Licensing  Executives Society Announces Distinguished Board of Directors
for 2019-2020 Term</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em style="text-align: center;">Diverse Group Includes Intellectual  Property and Licensing Leaders Representing Innovation-Centered Organizations  of All Sizes and Types</em></p>
<p><strong>RESTON, Va.</strong> – Oct. 21, 2019 --<a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.  (LES)</a> has elected new members to its<a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/bot">Board of Directors</a> for 2019-2020. The additions  extend the organization's broad leadership representation from the licensing  industry, ensuring that LES continues to engage and empower those involved in  LES' intellectual property (IP) and standards communities while progressing  toward its goals.</p>
<p> "Welcome to the new LES Board of  directors, a diverse group with strong leadership skills and broad experience  in the licensing industry. Their abilities and expertise will enable LES to  continue moving forward energetically on our important initiatives,  contributing to the advancement of our members and our sectors," said  outgoing LES President and Chair <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/trusteebios#held">Bob Held</a>.</p>
<p> As part of the Executive Committee's  seamless leadership transition, <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/trusteebios#fedorochko">Gary Fedorochko</a>, previously LES'  president-elect, moves into the role of president and chair of LES. Director <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/trusteebios#fenton">Gillian Fenton</a> has been named president-  and chair-elect, and <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/trusteebios#kreppel">Rachel Kreppel</a> is now counsel to the board.</p>
<p> "I'm grateful for this  opportunity to serve LES and represent our members. I am committed to working  diligently to advance the LES vision and mission and hope to connect and  inspire everyone involved in LES and the broader licensing industry," said  Fedorochko. "On behalf of the Board, I would like to thank Bob Held for his dedicated service to LES during his term as President and Chair. Bob’s commitment and leadership has provided me with a roadmap to continue enhancing LES.”</p>
<p>  The full roster, including photos and  biographies, is available on the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/bot">LES website</a>.</p>
<p> <strong>2019-2020  Executive Committee</strong><br />
President and Chair of the Board – Gary Fedorochko<br />
President-Elect and Chair-Elect of the Board – Gillian  Fenton<br />
Immediate Past-President and Past-Chair of the Board –  Bob Held<br />
Secretary – Kevin Spivak<br />
Treasurer – Mike Pellegrino<br />
Counsel – Rachel Kreppel</p>
<p><strong>New  2019-2020 Directors</strong><br />
Jim Bratton<br />
Ann Cannoni<br />
Evelyn Chen<br />
Ian DiBernardo<br />
Lalit Gaur<br />
Louise Levien<br />
Annemarie Meike <br />
Lesley Millar-Nicholson<br />
Karthika Perumal<br />
Karen Temple<br />
Eric Victory<br />
Scott Williams</p>
<p> <strong>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</strong><br />
Established in 1965, Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of  2,500 members engaged in the creation, commercial development and orderly  transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of  intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards  development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model  innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists, engineers, IP valuation  experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition  experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain  managers, tax specialists and technology transfer specialists. These members  represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds -- such as  government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating  companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms and trade  associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society  International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 8,000  members in 90 countries. For more information about LES, go to<a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">###</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 20:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES to Honor 15th Annual Deals of Distinction Award Winners at its Phoenix Annual Meeting, Oct 21-23</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=471569</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=471569</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><em><u>For more information:</u></em><br>
  Jessie  Hennion<br>
  LES  PR Director<br>
  <a href="mailto:jhennion@virtualinc.com">jhennion@virtualinc.com</a> <br>
  +1  781-876-6280</p>
<p><u>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</u><u> </u></p>
<h2 align="center"><strong>LES to Honor 15th Annual Deals of  Distinction™ Award Winners at its Phoenix Annual Meeting, October 21-23</strong></h2>
<p align="center"><em>LES Members to Be Recognized for  Outstanding Achievements in the Field of Licensing Business Deals at LES 2019  Annual Meeting in Phoenix, October 21</em></p>
<p><strong>RESTON, VA. – Sept. 30, 2019</strong> -- The  Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A and Canada), Inc. (<a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/">LES</a>) today  announced the recipients of its <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/dda">Deals of Distinction™ Awards</a> in four industry sectors. The  annual program, now in its fifteenth year, recognizes the LES member companies  that orchestrated the year's most outstanding licensing and business deals in  each sector. The awards will be presented during the <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/">LES Annual Meeting</a> Award Luncheon, Monday, October 21, 2019, at the <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/venue/">Phoenix JW Marriott Desert Ridge Resort & Spa</a>. Several key dealmakers will be on  hand to provide insights on their winning deals.</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://lesmeetings.org/">Register today for the LES Annual Meeting, Oct. 21-23, in  Phoenix</a></li>
</ul>
<p>" Through well-organized commercialization of intellectual property, we can drive growth across all business sectors in our global economy, from traditional business products to emerging product technologies. The 2019 award winners demonstrate exciting and impactful innovations within the licensing industry, and we are pleased to recognize their success," said LES President and Chair Bob Held. "At our Annual  Meeting in Phoenix, we'll celebrate these deals in a variety of ways, as well as hearing from our members and the dealmakers themselves, about the key aspects of those deals. Our thanks go to the Awards Committee for highlighting  the continued achievements of LES members."</p>
<p>This year's <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/dda">Deals of Distinction™ Award</a><u> </u>recipients include:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Chemicals, Energy, Environment &  Materials Sector</strong>:  Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Commonwealth Fusion Systems -- <em>MIT and Commonwealth Fusion Systems launch  novel approach to fusion power</em></li>
  <li><strong>High Technology Sector</strong>: Sisvel International S.A. and RPX  Corporation -- <em>"Aggregator meets  Aggregator": Sisvel and RPX ink major Wi-Fi SEP licensing deal</em></li>
  <li><strong>Industry-University-Government  Interface Sector</strong>:  Oregon Health & Science University and the University of Pittsburgh;  Ultragenyx Pharmaceutical Inc. -- <em>Rare  pediatric disease dataset license</em></li>
  <li><strong>Life Sciences Sector</strong>: Dicerna Pharmaceuticals and Eli  Lilly and Company - <em>Global licensing and research collaboration focused on  the discovery, development and commercialization of RNAi therapies in  cardio-metabolic disease, neurodegeneration and pain.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>All LES members  attending the Annual Meeting are invited to the Award Luncheon. Additional  information about the October 20-23 LES Annual Meeting, including registration  instructions, can be found at <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/">https://lesmeetings.org/</a>. Previous honorees and  their award-winning deals are listed at <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/?dda">www.lesusacanada.org/?dda</a>. </p>
<p><strong>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</strong><br>
  Established in 1965, Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of  2,500 members engaged in the creation, commercial development and orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists, engineers, IP valuation experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain managers, tax specialists and technology transfer specialists. These members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds -- such as government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms and trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society  International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 8,000  members in 90 countries. For more information about LES, go to <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a>. </p>
<p align="center">###</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 14:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES Annual Meeting Brings Together World-Renowned Speakers and Cutting-Edge Programming, Oct 20-23</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=462923</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=462923</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>For Immediate Release</strong> <br>
  Jessie Hennion <br>
  LES Public Relations <br>
  <a href="mailto:jhennion@virtualinc.com">jhennion@virtualinc.com</a> <br>
  +1 781-976-6280 </p>
<h2 align="center"><strong>Licensing Executives Society’s Annual Meeting Brings  Together World-Renowned Speakers and Cutting-Edge Programming, October 20-23, in  Phoenix</strong><strong> </strong></h2>
<p align="center"><em>LES Annual Meeting’s Multi-Track Program Will  Offer Attendees Industry-Wide and Sector-Specific Content Delivered by a  World-Class Lineup of Speakers.</em></p>
<p><strong>RESTON, Va. </strong>-- July 30, 2019 -- The <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A.  and Canada)</a> today announced the speaker  lineup and topics for the <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/">LES 2019 Annual Meeting,</a> October 20-23, 2019, at the Phoenix <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/venue/" target="_blank">JW  Marriott Desert Ridge Resort & Spa</a>. The highly anticipated three-day event  is expected to convene more than hundreds of executives and will feature a  speaker roster of notable business leaders and members of the licensing and intellectual  capital management communities. Registration and conference information are available at <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/">https://lesmeetings.org/</a></p>
<p>This year’s meeting features nearly 70 sessions with more than 100 expert  speakers, including keynote speakers <a href="https://www.justice.gov/atr/staff-profile/meet-assistant-attorney-general" target="_blank">Assistant  Attorney General of the Antitrust Division of the U.S. Department of Justice Makan Delrahim</a>, <a href="https://internethalloffame.org/vint-cerf" target="_blank">Google Vice President and Chief Internet  Evangelist Vinton Cerf</a>, Microsoft Managing Director for  Startups <a href="https://startups.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/shaloo-garg-joins-microsoft-for-startups-team/" target="_blank">Shaloo Garg</a>, and many <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/schedule/speakers//">more</a>. </p>
<p align="center"><img border="0"  src="https://www.lesusacanada.org/resource/resmgr/2019_meetings/keynotepr.png"></p>
<p>"The impressive 2019  Annual Meeting program showcases the role of LES at the forefront of the  evolving innovation economy," said LES President and Chairman Bob Held.  “Delivering on our mission to educate our members and position them for  success, this year's array of world-class speakers will offer ground-breaking  perspectives and authoritative insights into the topics most important to  today's industry professionals. It's the one event this year that anyone  involved in IP and licensing can't afford to miss."</p>
<p>The Annual Meeting will bring  IP and licensing professional groups together to network, collaborate and discuss  some of the most critical issues facing the industry. Highlights include: </p>
<ul>
  <li>Opening  Plenary Session with <a href="https://www.justice.gov/atr/staff-profile/meet-assistant-attorney-general" target="_blank">Assistant  Attorney General of the Antitrust Division of the U.S. Department of Justice Makan Delrahim</a></li>
  <li>“<a href="https://lesmeetings.org/agenda/">Patent Trial and Appeal Board Fireside Chat</a>” with speakers Paul Michel, Chief Judge, United States Court of Appeals for the Federal  Circuit, Retired; and <a href="https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/executive-biographies/scott-r-boalick" target="_blank">Scott R. Boalick</a>, Chief Judge for the Patent Trial  and Appeal Board (PTAB) at the U.S. Patent and Trade Office (USPTO) </li>
  <li><a href="https://lesmeetings.org/agenda/">Sessions and educational panels</a> that will explore the development and  protection of IP commerce, licensing, intellectual capital management and the <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards">LES  Standards Initiative</a></li>
  <li>The <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/dda">LES Deals of Distinction Award</a> will be presented to companies that  orchestrated the year’s most outstanding licensing and business deals in each  sector. Several key dealmakers will be on hand to provide insights on their  winning deals.</li>
  <li>Opportunity to meet with sector leaders  to discuss the results of LES <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/members/group_content_view.asp?group=160354&id=787908">High Tech Sector</a>,  and <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/members/group_content_view.asp?group=160356&id=559828">Life Sciences Sector</a> Royalty  Rates & Deal Terms Surveys - an analysis of exclusive findings and compelling  trends gleaned from the investigation of thousands of licensing agreements. </li>
</ul>
<p>In addition to the keynote  speakers, <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/sectors">LES  sector</a> experts have designed  customized tracks with educational sessions, interactive workshops and  networking opportunities to enhance engagement and to maximize the meeting’s  value for attendees in every sector.</p>
<p>LES  would like to give special thanks to its <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/sponsors-2/">2019  Annual Meeting sponsors and media partners</a>. For more information about the conference, sponsorships or registration, visit <a href="https://lesmeetings.org/">https://lesmeetings.org/</a>. </p>
<p><strong>About  Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</strong> <br>
  Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A.  and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of 2,500 members engaged in  the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual  property rights; protection and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards  development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model  innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists, engineers, IP valuation  experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition  experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain  managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members  represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such as  government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating  companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade  associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society  International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 8,000  members in 90 countries.<a href="http://lesusacanada.org/">www.lesusacanada.org</a>. </p>
<p align="center">### </p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Licensing Executives Society Applauds Introduction  of the  STRONGER Patents Act of 2019</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=461478</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=461478</guid>
<description><![CDATA[RESTON, VIRGINIA — July 17, 2019 —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</a>&nbsp;(LES) commends Senator Coons, Representative Stivers and other co-sponsors for reintroducing the bipartisan STRONGER Patents Act of 2019 in the Senate and the House of Representatives.&nbsp; We commend these members of Congress for their leadership, and for their collaborative spirit in securing co-sponsors from both sides of the aisle in both houses of Congress.&nbsp;<br />
<p>If enacted, this legislation will strengthen the U.S. patent system, reduce abuse, and ameliorate many of the unintended consequences that have crept into the U.S. patent system since the passage of the America Invents Act (AIA), and as a result of a series of unfortunate court decisions.&nbsp; With the STRONGER Patents Act of 2019, Congress will re-affirm innovation and intellectual property rights as pillars of the American economy, and will regain its proper role in setting prudent IP policy.&nbsp; </p>
<p>The American inventor is the embodiment of the pioneering spirit that made the U.S. economy the envy of the world.&nbsp; Our innovative spirit has been fueled by a patent system conferring a valuable property right on inventors – the right to exclude others from exploiting the inventor’s creation.&nbsp; Without that property right, innovation withers, investment declines, and economic activity is diminished.&nbsp; By increasing the strength and durability of U.S. patents, inventors more actively create, the public enjoys those creations, and new industries flourish.&nbsp; LES is committed to working with Congress and the executive branch on initiatives to further improve the U.S. patent system, including industry self-regulation to build consensus and to promote prudent IP practices (LES Standards Initiative, <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards">https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards</a>).&nbsp;&nbsp; Over the past several years, the U.S. patent system has lost its place as the perennial world leader in value, reliability, and durability.&nbsp; (<a href="https://www.theglobalipcenter.com/u-s-chamber-releases-2019-international-ip-index/">https://www.theglobalipcenter.com/u-s-chamber-releases-2019-international-ip-index/</a>).&nbsp; We need to reverse that trend.&nbsp; The STRONGER Patents Act of 2019 is an important step in that direction.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="margin: 0px 0px 10px;"><span>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.:</span><br />
Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of 2,500 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists, engineers, IP valuation experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such as government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 8,000 members in 90 countries.<a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/" style="background: 0px 0px;">www.lesusacanada.org</a></p>
<p style="margin: 0px 0px 10px; text-align: center;">###</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/resource/resmgr/docs/news/stronger_patents_act_of_2019.pdf">Download Press Release here</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 19:08:32 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES Statement on Tillis-Coons Proposal for Patent Eligibility Reform</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=454648</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=454648</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h2 align="center">Licensing Executives Society  Statement on 
  Tillis-Coons Proposal for Patent Eligibility Reform</h2>
<p align="center"><em><strong>Bill  Would Restore Certainty, and Revitalize Incentives for Innovation</strong></em></p>
<p>RESTON, VIRGINIA — June  5, 2019 — <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</a> commends  Senators Tillis and Coons, and Representatives Collins, Johnson, and Stivers,  in their proposed language for a bill to reform Section 101 of the Patent Act. This is sensible reform that will improve our patent system and further encourage innovation. </p>
<p> This draft legislation is an important step forward in restoring certainty to our patent system. The innovative American spirit has been supported and encouraged by a patent system designed and implemented to reward inventors by affording them an exclusive right to their inventions. A system that affords predictable  and reliable legal protections to a vast array of products and processes  improves the human condition, encourages the devotion of time and talent to  their creation, and attracts investment in new industries and businesses.</p>
<p>Recently,  the law of patent eligibility has been altered by judicial decisions confusing distinct legal principles of what constitutes the act of invention with what field of endeavor should be eligible for protection. Throughout much of its history, the U.S. patent system used patent eligibility as a crude filter merely to ensure that patent protection was properly limited by the  Constitutional mandate to promote the progress of useful arts. As such, <em>useful</em> inventions were the touchstone of  patent eligibility. Other sections of the law dealt with the merits of the particular claimed invention. The confusion of those distinct legal principles caused our patent system to suffer from increased uncertainty and diminished reliance, and our economy suffered from a corresponding reduction in investment. </p>
<p>Judicial  decisions are necessarily <em>ad hoc</em>,  born of specific facts giving rise to peculiar disputes. Precedent is a poor vehicle for policy. Congress is right to resume its rightful role in setting our nation’s patent policy by reiterating and restoring the traditional notion of patent eligibility as a broad and inclusive concept. In so doing, and in giving it the force and effect of law, Congress would further encourage innovation in wide-ranging and diverse fields of endeavor thereby bringing new products and processes into being for the benefit of all of humanity. </p>
<p><strong>About  Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.:</strong><br>
  Established in 1965, Licensing Executives  Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of 2,500  members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists,  engineers, IP valuation experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists,  merger and acquisition experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such as government laboratories, professional services firms,  universities, operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing  Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies  representing 8,000 members in 90 countries.<a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">www.lesusacanada.org</a></p>
<p align="center">###</p>
<p><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/resource/resmgr/news/LES_Statement_on_Tillis_and_.pdf" target="_blank">Download the press release here.</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 5 Jun 2019 17:43:47 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES Society to Welcome Former USPTO Director and Distinguished Leaders at Silicon Valley USPTO Event</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=442409</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=442409</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE </strong><br>
  Jessie  Hennion<br>
  LES Public Relations<br>
  <a href="mailto:jhennion@virtualinc.com">jhennion@virtualinc.com</a> <br>
  781.876.6280</p>
<h2 align="center"><strong>Licensing Executives Society to Welcome Former USPTO  Director and Distinguished Leaders at Silicon Valley USPTO Event on May 14,  2019</strong></h2>
<p align="center"><em>LES Draws </em><em>Top Technology, Licensing, and IP Minds  for a Day of Interactive Discussion </em><em>on How Intellectual  Capital Management and Standards Can Enhance the Innovation Economy</em></p>
<p><strong>San  Jose, Calif. </strong>-- March 20, 2019 -- The <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">Licensing Executives Society</a> (U.S.A. and  Canada), Inc. (LES) announced today that registration is open for its inaugural <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/leadingedge">LES Leading Edge Series</a> event, <a href="http://lesmeetings.org/leadingedge/standards-in-icm/">Driving  Innovation: Standards in Licensing and Intellectual Capital Management</a>, at the Silicon Valley U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (<a href="https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/uspto-locations/silicon-valley-california">USPTO</a>) in San Jose.  The highly anticipated, one-day event will feature a speaker line-up of notable  business leaders and members of the technology and intellectual property (IP)  communities. The full agenda  and speaker list are available on the LES  website <a href="http://lesmeetings.org/leadingedge/standards-in-icm/#agenda">here</a>.  Early bird registration pricing is available through March 29, 2019. </p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/events/EventDetails.aspx?id=1184152&group=">Register for the May 14th LES Event  at the USPTO titled Driving Innovation: Standards in Licensing and Intellectual  Capital Management</a></li>
</ul>
<p>“We’re  thrilled to have <strong>Cravath, Swaine & Moore Partner David Kappos, former  Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the USPTO,  as well as </strong>Silicon Valley USPTO  Director John Cabeca among the world-class  speakers we have assembled for our inaugural LES Leading Edge Series event,”  said LES President and Chair Bob Held. “It will be a high-level educational  experience for technology and IP professionals looking for cutting-edge  information on how intellectual capital management and standards enhance  success in the innovation economy.”</p>
<p>Kappos will deliver the  LES keynote titled “Behavioral Issues in Licensing of SEPs and other IP — Defining  Acceptable and Best Practices through Voluntary Standards.” As <strong>Under  Secretary of Commerce</strong> and  Director of the USPTO, <strong>Kappos</strong> was instrumental in achieving  legislative reform of the U.S. patent system. He is widely recognized as one of the world’s foremost leaders in the field of intellectual capital, including IP  management and strategy; the development of global IP norms, laws and practice;  and the commercialization and enforcement of innovation-based assets. </p>
<p>Among the featured LES Leading Edge  Series event <a href="http://lesmeetings.org/leadingedge/standards-in-icm/#agenda">speakers,  moderators and panelists</a> will be business and technology  leaders from Avanci; Avasta Incorporated;  Center for Intellectual Property; Collins Aerospace; Cravath, Swaine &  Moore; Ericsson; Finjan Holdings, Inc.; GE Ventures; InventionShare; PIUS  Limited, LLC; Prasad IP, PC; Science Futures, Inc.; Stout Risius Ross, LLC;  Tangible IP; The Boeing Company; USPTO; and Visa among others. </p>
<p> Program topics will explore some of the biggest challenges technologists and IP  professionals face today and reveal best practices around intellectual capital management and standards. Session highlights include:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Standards  in Licensing and Intellectual Capital Management</li>
  <li>Innovation,  Interoperability and Efficiency Through  Standards</li>
  <li>Improving  IP Valuation Outcomes Through the Use of Standards</li>
  <li>IP  Management for Startups</li>
  <li>Intangible  Assets in the Boardroom </li>
</ul>
<p>For more information about the conference, sponsorships or registration, visit <a href="http://lesmeetings.org/leadingedge/standards-in-icm/">http://lesmeetings.org/leadingedge/standards-in-icm/</a></p>
<p>About<strong> the </strong><strong>Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. </strong><br>
  Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a  professional society of 2,500 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists, engineers, IP valuation experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such as government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society  International, Inc. (LESI), which has 33 societies representing more than 8,000  members in 90 countries. <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center">###</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES Unveils Results of Groundbreaking High Tech Sector Royalty Rates &amp; Deal Terms Survey</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=439992</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=439992</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 align="center">Licensing Executives Society Unveils Results of  Groundbreaking <strong>High  Tech Sector Royalty Rates & Deal Terms Survey</strong></h1>
<p align="center"><em>Survey Results Offer an Inside Look at Deal Dynamics  across a Wide Range of High Tech Sectors from Aerospace, Computing,  Communications to Electronics, Medical, and Beyond.</em></p>
<p>RESTON,  VIRGINIA — March 5, 2019 — <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</a> today announced the results of its third, comprehensive <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/members/group_content_view.asp?group=160354&id=787908">LES  High Tech Sector Royalty Rates & Deal Terms Survey</a>. Conducted  by LES High Tech Sector in coordination with LES, the survey addresses the  elusive gaps in industry-specific deals and trends. The LES High Tech Sector  Royalty Rates & Deal Terms Survey is available free-of-charge to <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/members/group_content_view.asp?group=160354&id=787908">members  to download</a>, and  non-members may purchase the report <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/store/ViewProduct.aspx?id=13325916">here</a>. </p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/members/group_content_view.asp?group=160354&id=787908">Learn  more about the LES High Tech Sector Royalty Rates & Deal Terms Survey  Report </a></li>
  <li><a href="http://lesmeetings.org/leadingedge/standards-in-icm/">Register for the LES Leading Edge Series event at  the USPTO-Silicon Valley in San Jose</a></li>
</ul>
<p>"Much  has changed in the world of patents and IP licensing. The LES High Tech Sector  Royalty Rates & Deal Terms Survey provides access to rare industry-specific  data on sector IP licensing royalty rates and deal  terms not available from other sources," said LES President and Chair <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/page/trusteebios">Bob Held</a>. "Due  to the effects of the America Invents Act and other judicial rulings, the  report data indicates that the sector is increasingly relying on collaborations  and deal-making as part of high-tech growth initiatives. As always, we thank  all the participants in the survey as well as the LES Survey Committee and  Vault Consulting for their work in fielding the survey, analyzing the results  and generating the final report." </p>
<p><strong>LES  High Tech Sector Royalty Rates & Deal Terms Survey</strong><br>
The survey went out to  approximately 2,469 LES members and 17,431 non-members, resulting in a higher  response rate of 6.3% compared with 5% in 2014. A total of 155 specific  intellectual property deals transacted between 2014 and 2017 were analyzed.  Deals of all types were submitted including sales and licenses; out-licenses  and in-licenses; lump sum and running royalty; and flat and tiered loyalty. </p>
<p>"The valuable data we've  gathered through the LES High Tech Sector Royalty Rates & Deal Terms Survey  is not available from other public and commercial sources and reveals much more  insight into the dynamics of the licensing market, given that we have the  unique ability to analyze and compare the transaction-level data going back to  2008," said <a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/page/mgtcouncilbios">Jack  Lu</a>, Ph.D., CFA, LES <em>Senior Vice President of Economic Analysis and Survey,  and a </em>Partner and Chief Economist of  IPMAP, LLC.</p>
<p><strong>Survey Highlights</strong> <br>
  The LES High Tech Sector Royalty Rates & Deal  Terms Survey<u> </u>addresses major fields  including aerospace, software, clean technology, communications, medical  devices, semiconductors, consumer products, electronics, and computers. Highlights  gleaned from the 155 distinct deals include:</p>
<ul>
  <li>88% of respondents were  licensors with 35% having entered into deals for monetary gains; 28% for  strategic purposes; 11% for a Standards Essential Patent (SEP) licensing; and  10% as part of an assertion strategy </li>
  <li>67% or two-thirds of deals  had an academic or governmental licensor</li>
  <li>61% of IP licensed assets  included patents; 36% had software, copyrights or trademarks; and 34% had  know-how or trade secret components</li>
  <li>48% of deals were exclusive  grants and 45% were non-exclusive</li>
  <li>36% of the licensed  technology was either in production or fully developed. The aerospace industry had  the highest average royalty rates at 11.69%, a 7% increase over the 2014 survey</li>
  <li>35% of licensors entered  into deals to support new products, a 13% increase over the 2014 survey</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Survey  Design and Methodology</strong> <br>
  The surveys were  designed by committees of experienced LES members within the High Tech Sector  who worked alongside an independent team from Vault Consulting on design,  dissemination, data collection, and analysis to ensure confidentiality. Vault Consulting enabled LES to issue and  collect the results while keeping the identities of the submitters  confidential, as LES  has done with all  of its previous deal term and royalty rate surveys.</p>
<p><strong>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada),  Inc.:</strong><br>
  Established in 1965, Licensing Executives  Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of 2,500  members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer  of intellectual property rights; protection and management of intellectual  capital; and intellectual capital  management standards development. LES members are accountants, business  leaders, business model innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists,  engineers, IP valuation experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists,  merger and acquisition experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic  planners, supply chain managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer  specialists. These members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all  sizes and kinds—such as government laboratories, professional services firms,  universities, operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty  firms, and trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing  Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies  representing 8,500 members in 90 countries.<a href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/">www.lesusacanada.org</a></p>
]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 5 Mar 2019 11:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES Issues Statement Commending the USPTO&apos;s Andrei Iancu for his Leadership </title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=424741</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=424741</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE </strong><br />
Contact: <br />
Kelli Baxter, Deputy Executive  Director, COO<br />
703-234-4088  | <a href="mailto:kbaxter@les.org">kbaxter@les.org</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) Issues  Statement Commending the </strong><strong>United States Patent and Trademark Office's Andrei Iancu for  his Leadership</strong><strong> </strong></h2>
<p>RESTON,  VIRGINIA—Oct. 30, 2018— <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES)</a> today issued the following statement commending the  Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the  United States Patent and Trademark Office ("USPTO") Andrei Iancu for his  leadership.</p>
<p>"We thank the  USPTO's Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of  the United States Patent and Trademark Office Andrei Iancu for his leadership in  adopting and publishing a Final Rule changing the claim construction standard  in various proceedings before the USPTO, including inter partes review."</p>
<p>"Prior to the rule change, the USPTO used the broadest reasonable interpretation when construing claims in post-grant proceedings before the Patent Trial and Appeal  Board (PTAB). However, district courts used the Phillips standard, which interprets the claims based on the view of one of skill in the art at the time the invention is made. Because two different standards were applied,  consistency and predictability for patent owners were compromised. In particular, patent owners were subject to expensive and time-consuming litigation in multiple forums – the UPSTO and one or more district courts –  where different results could occur because of the different standards. These inconsistent claim construction standards led to weakening our patent system. This,  in turn, discourages innovation, reduces investment, and hinders the formation  of new businesses and industries."</p>
<p>"LES is a  non-partisan, non-profit, volunteer-driven professional society devoted to speeding innovation to market. For over 50 years, we have been the only society devoted exclusively to&nbsp;<span>professionals representing innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds. LES’</span><span> vision is to connect and inspire the broad diversity of people involved in IP, intellectual capital management, and ICM standards development</span>. We represent all industries, from high technology to pharma/biotech.  Our members are inventors, entrepreneurs, business executives, accountants, and lawyers. And, we represent licensors as well as licensees. In short, we represent all sides in all quadrants of the innovation economy. We are devoted  to the principle that intellectual property is a private property right that  must be respected like any other form of private property – through  predictable, reliable, and durable legal rights that are worthy of investment  and command the respect of the market."</p>
<p>"The adoption of the Final Rule changing the claim construction standard is welcome and supported by LES. This rule will encourage innovation and investment into  intellectual property because it creates more consistent outcomes."</p>
<p><strong><em>About  the Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. </em></strong> <br />
Established in 1965, Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of more than 2,200 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards development. LES members are business leaders, accountants, economists, IP  valuation experts, supply chain managers, lawyers, technology transfer specialists, public policy leaders, lobbyists, mergers and acquisitions experts, tax specialists, deal-makers, strategic planners, business model innovators, consultants, engineers, licensing executives, and scientists. These members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds— such as government laboratories, professional services firms, universities,  operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society  International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 10,000  members in 90 countries. <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">###</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) Welcomes Newly-Elected 2018-19 Board Members</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=422882</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=422882</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE </strong><br />
Contact: <br />
Kelli Baxter, Deputy Executive  Director, COO<br />
703-234-4088  | <a href="mailto:kbaxter@les.org">kbaxter@les.org</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) Welcomes Newly-Elected 2018-19 Board  Members</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>New 2018-19 LES Board of Directors to Begin  Term at Annual Meeting in Boston and Bring Distinctive Knowledge and Subject  Matter Expertise to LES' Strategic Growth Areas.</em></p>
<p>RESTON,  VIRGINIA—Oct. 16, 2018— <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES)</a> is pleased to announce the <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/bot">2018-19 Board of Directors</a>.  The additions ensure broad leadership representation from the licensing  industry, enabling LES to empower members from notable business leaders to  professionals involved in LES' intellectual property (IP), intellectual capital  management (ICM) and ICM standards communities.</p>
<p>"Our new  board of directors has each made significant contributions to the IP industry  and LES standards initiatives, enabling LES to move forward energetically on  our leadership and educational initiatives," said LES CEO Kim Chotkowski. "I  look forward to working with this new slate of dedicated volunteers whose  viewpoints and contributions will help LES make significant contributions to  our industry and LES."</p>
<p><strong>Executive Committee Appoints 2018-19 President and Chair</strong><br />
As part of  the Executive Committee's seamless leadership transition, Bob Held, previously  LES' president-elect, moves into the role of President and Chair of LES. </p>
<p>"I am truly honored to  continue to serve the licensing industry and represent the leaders of LES. I  believe strongly in LES' vision to  connect and inspire the broad diversity of people involved in IP, intellectual capital management, and ICM  standards development," Held said. "On behalf of the Board, I would like to  thank Bill Elkington for his  extraordinary contributions and outstanding leadership as the LES President and  Chair for the 2017-18 term. I look forward to leading the way in preparing our  members for the opportunities of the future."</p>
<p>Congratulations  to the following newly elected LES leaders. The full roster including photos  and full biographies is available on the <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/bot">LES website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>2018-2019 Board of Directors </strong><br />
President and  Chair of the Board - Bob Held<br />
President-Elect  and Chair-Elect of the Board - Gary Fedorochko<br />
Immediate  Past-President and Past-Chair of the Board - Bill Elkington<br />
Secretary -  Kevin Spivak<br />
Treasurer -  Mike Pellegrino<br />
Counsel -  Paul A. Roberts</p>
<p><strong>2018-2019 Directors</strong><br />
Jim Bratton<br />
Gillian Fenton<br />
Annie  Gauthier<br />
Rachel  Kreppel<br />
Louise Levien<br />
Matthew  McNeill<br />
Annemarie  Meike&nbsp;<br />
Lesley  Millar-Nicholson<br />
Eric Victory<br />
Scott  Williams</p>
<p><strong><em>About the Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. </em></strong> <br />
Established in 1965, Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of  3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly  transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of  intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards  development. LES members are business leaders, accountants, economists, IP  valuation experts, supply chain managers, lawyers, technology transfer  specialists, public policy leaders, lobbyists, mergers and acquisitions  experts, tax specialists, deal-makers, strategic planners, business model  innovators, consultants, engineers, licensing executives, and scientists. These  members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such  as government laboratories, professional services firms, universities,  operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and  trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society  International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 10,000  members in 90 countries. <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">###<br />
</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 17:52:40 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES Launches New FRAND Licensing Standard Committee </title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=422295</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=422295</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span>Contact: </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span>Kelli Baxter, Deputy Executive Director, COO</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span>703-234-4088 | <span><a href="mailto:kbaxter@les.org">kbaxter@les.org</a></span></span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><b><span>Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) Launches New&nbsp;</span></b><b>FRAND Licensing Standard Committee</b></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><i><span>LES Invites Enterprises and Individuals to Join the FRAND Licensing Standard Committee and Help Reduce the Cost and Management Time Involved in Licensing Standard-Essential Patents.</span></i></p>
<p><span>RESTON, VIRGINIA—Oct. 12, 2018 —</span><span> <span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES)</a></span> today announced that its ANSI-accredited LES Standards program has established the <span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards">LES FRAND Licensing Standard Committee</a></span>. The group will focus on the creation of an industry-wide, consensus-based business process standard that ensures that all parties have a clear understanding of their responsibilities in the FRAND (Fair, Reasonable and Non-Discriminatory) standard-essential patents (SEP) licensing process. The committee brings together industry experts and LES Standards program members who engage as principals or agents in the practice of licensing SEPs on FRAND terms. By collaborating on best practices to provide this clarity, the resulting standard will reduce the cost and the management time to license SEPs.</span></p>
<p><span>Members and non-members are invited to <span><a href="https://cc.readytalk.com/registration/#/?meeting=dvyqqu3g7m7u&amp;campaign=tnm3fgeznx33">register for a free, introductory call</a></span> with the Committee Co-Chairs on Wednesday, Oct. 17 at 3:00 p.m. Eastern.</span></p>
<ul>
    <li><span><b><span><a href="https://cc.readytalk.com/registration/#/?meeting=dvyqqu3g7m7u&amp;campaign=tnm3fgeznx33">Register for the Free, Introductory Call to Learn More About the Committee</a></span></b></span><b><span> </span></b></li>
    <li><span><b><span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/frandqa">Read the LES FRAND Licensing Standards Committee Q&amp;A with the Co-Chairs</a> </span></b></span></li>
    <li><span><b><span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards">Join the LES Standards Initiative and FRAND Licensing Standards Committee</a></span></b></span></li>
</ul>
<p><span>Current members of the LES FRAND Licensing Standards Committee are representatives from ACT | The App Association, Ericsson, Essential Patent, Held Intellectual Property, Hernandez IP, InterDigital, JusTech Law, Longhorn IP, Philips Intellectual Property &amp; Standards, Sisvel Group, Rockwell Collins, Teletry, Unified Patents, and many other leaders. To learn more about the Committee and its members, visit <span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/frandmembers">https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/frandmembers</a></span>.</span></p>
<p><span>“The developers and implementers of technical standards will benefit from a flexible and yet standardized framework for licensing SEPs on FRAND terms,” said <span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/trusteebios#held">Bob Held</a></span>, chair-elect and president-elect of LES. “We have therefore established a committee in LES Standards to spell out and enhance efficient industry best practices for this important area of the innovation ecosystem.”</span></p>
<p><span>The committee’s co-chairs are <span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards">LES Standards Program</a></span> members Matteo Sabattini, director of IP policy at Ericsson, and Brian Scarpelli, senior global policy counsel at ACT | The App Association. Matteo is currently responsible for IP rights policy and advocacy and promotion at standard defining/setting organizations (SDOs/SSOs), industry fora, trade associations, governmental agencies, etc. He has expertise in technology and IP-related matters, and his background combines business, policy and technical skills. Brian is responsible for legal and policy advocacy on a diversity of issues impacting small business software development and high tech companies, including standards, competition, and intellectual property.</span></p>
<p><span>“Matteo and Brian are ideal chairs of this committee because they represent stakeholders from throughout the innovation ecosystem,” said <span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/trusteebios#elkington">Bill Elkington</a></span>, current chair and president of LES. “As an ANSI-accredited standard developer in the field of intellectual capital management, and with Matteo’s and Brian’s leadership, LES is well-positioned to develop consensus guidance on FRAND licensing practices.”</span></p>
<p><span>This new standard will ensure that all parties have a clear understanding of their responsibilities in the SEP licensing process - reducing the cost and the management time to license SEPs. The FRAND licensing standard will be developed by experts in the field of SEP licensing, and LES invites the participation of all enterprises and individuals who may be affected by such a standard.</span></p>
<p><b><span>Get Involved in the LES FRAND Licensing Standard Committee</span></b></p>
<p><span>To become a member of the LES Standards program and FRAND Licensing Standard Committee, visit <span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards">https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards</a></span>. LES Standards members interested in joining the FRAND Licensing Standard Committee can register on the LES website <span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/general/pick_username.asp">here</a></span> and take advantage of participating in meetings and <span><a href="https://cc.readytalk.com/registration/#/?meeting=dvyqqu3g7m7u&amp;campaign=tnm3fgeznx33">calls</a></span> including the Face-to-Face meeting in D.C. on Oct. 29, 2018.</span></p>
<p><b><span>About the LES Standards Program </span></b></p>
<p><span>The LES Standards Program offers enterprises and individuals the best practices and standards they need to improve the way they do IP transactions, protect their innovation, use IP in their business strategies, and manage third-party IP. Accredited by the American National Standards Institute (ANSI), LES Standards program has <span><a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/lesstandards">eight active standards committees</a></span>: IP licensing, FRAND licensing, IP brokerage, IP protection in the supply chain, IP valuation, IP management for startups, intangible assets in the boardroom, and one committee providing commenting support for the ISO/TC279 Innovation Management Standard. LES Standards members include many diverse members of the innovation economy, including operating companies, (both large and small), universities (both public and private), IP valuation companies, IP consulting companies, IP brokers, and law firms. Membership in LES and LES Standards is open to all. Visit: <span><a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/?lesstandards">http://www.lesusacanada.org/?lesstandards</a></span>.</span></p>
<p><b><i><span>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. </span></i></b></p>
<p><span>Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of 3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards development. LES members are business leaders, accountants, economists, IP valuation experts, supply chain managers, lawyers, technology transfer specialists, public policy leaders, lobbyists, mergers and acquisitions experts, tax specialists, deal-makers, strategic planners, business model innovators, consultants, engineers, licensing executives, and scientists. These members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such as government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 10,000 members in 90 countries. <span><a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/">www.lesusacanada.org</a></span>.</span></p>
<p><span>&nbsp;</span></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES Proposes New Way For Boards To Oversee Material Intangible Assets Currently Ignored</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=422156</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=422156</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><b>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE<br />
</b>Contact: <br />
Kelli Baxter, Deputy Executive Director, COO<br />
703-234-4088 | <a href="mailto:kbaxter@les.org">kbaxter@les.org</a></p>
<p>Nicholas Gaffney<br />
Zumado Public Relations<br />
415-377-1131 | <a href="mailto:ngaffney@zumado.com">ngaffney@zumado.com</a></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) Proposes New Way For Boards To Oversee Material Intangible Assets Currently Ignored</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><i>LES' IA in the Boardroom Standard Could Impact Board Liability in Overseeing Increasingly Important IA</i></p>
<p>RESTON, VA –Oct. 11, 2018‑-— <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) (LES)</a> Standards Development Organization (SDO) board will vote on the first draft of LES' Intangible Assets (IA, which includes&nbsp;among other things, intellectual property, supply chain contracts, customer relationships, assembled workforce and franchise rights) in the Boardroom standard at its upcoming <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/">annual meeting</a> in Boston at the Marriott Copley Place, Oct. 14 -18, 2018.</p>
<p>The draft standard is the first of its kind to address company directors' duty to adequately oversee IA value and risk. Specifically, it provides a set of principles as well as a reliable framework and process for that IA oversight. Notably, the draft standard addresses in-depth what Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP) may not address adequately or consistently, which could have a permanent effect on accounting standards and board-related IA litigation.</p>
<p>"We've had sound principles for valuing tangible and financial assets for the past 60 years, but there hasn't been a reliable equivalent for board-oversight of the management of intangible assets until now," said <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/trusteebios#elkington">Bill Elkington, LES president and chair and senior director of IP management at Rockwell Collins</a>. "Company directors have a duty to maximize shareholder value and manage risks. Some of them have been sued by shareholders because they didn't address intangible assets adequately, and this has negatively affected company reputations and bottom lines."</p>
<p>While the IA in the Boardroom standard faces a long approval process like any other industry standard, its effect on accounting and litigation could be profound. For example, current accounting standards including GAAP and International Financial Reporting Standards may not address IA in a manner that is consistent with the growing importance of IA in the modern global economy. For example, traditional accounting provides for different treatment for the same assets created within a first company as compared to a second company that acquires those exact same assets from the creator.</p>
<p>This sort of inconsistent treatment has become increasingly concerning at a time when IA are increasingly important to company value and risk. Many of today's disruptive business models&nbsp;depend predominantly on intangible assets, for example, Uber doesn't own automobiles and Airbnb doesn't own hotel rooms. In fact, the World Intellectual Property Organization, a United Nations agency, reported in 2017 that intangible assets add twice as much value to products as tangible capital, across nineteen global value chains, according to their ground-breaking original research.</p>
<p>Similarly, IA-related litigation could be impacted permanently. Specifically, directors who comply with the standard could demonstrate they acted responsibly. Conversely, directors who fail to comply with the standard could find that fact used against them in court to show negligence or misconduct.</p>
<p>The IA in the Boardroom standard is comprehensive. It includes a set of core principles, a common AI language for boards, an agnostic approach to materiality and risk tolerance, and a five-step process for implementing the standard.</p>
<p>"Directors need a rigorous way of separating intangible asset value from tangible asset and human capital value. They also need a way of identifying material intangible assets so they can understand the respective impact of each on the value of, and risk to, the company," said <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/paul-roberts-556176">Paul Roberts, in his capacity as LES board counsel and co-founding chair of the Intangible Asset in Boardroom (proposed) standard</a>. "The IA in the Boardroom standard provides an agnostic way of doing that, which is important since every company is unique. It would be disingenuous to prescribe a single model that applies in the same way to companies of all sizes, in all industries and at all stages of development."</p>
<p><b>First Public Discussion of Draft Standard</b></p>
<p>LES will present a <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/session/pre-meeting-workshop-intangible-assets-in-the-boardroom/">pre-meeting workshop</a> on Sunday, October 14, 2018, to discuss the key aspects of the draft standard. This will be the first public discussion of its content, which will include:</p>
<ul style="margin-top: 0in; list-style-type: disc;">
    <li>Identifying changes in the financial and legal environments that impact a board's ability to effectively discharge their IA oversight responsibilities;</li>
    <li>Articulating the core principles for appropriate board IA oversight;</li>
    <li>Creating a taxonomy for translating between business and legal terminology to lower existing communication barriers between directors and IA professionals; and</li>
    <li>Developing a "materiality filter" that enables the standard to be applied in a way that reflects the differences in company size, maturity, technology, culture, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>The workshop panel will be chaired by Roberts. Panel participants include Edgar Baum, chief executive officer and chief brand economist at brand economics firm Strata Insights; John Carney, managing director of product design and manufacturing process, asset sales and market supply consultancy China IP exchange; and Ron Laurie, chairman of breakthrough invention fund InventionShare.</p>
<p><b>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.: </b></p>
<p>Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of 3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists, engineers, IP valuation experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such as government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 10,000 members in 90 countries. <u><a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/">www.lesusacanada.org</a></u></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><b>###</b></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 13:37:23 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jim McCarthy To Receive Licensing Executives Society&apos;s (U.S.A. and Canada) Highest Honor</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=421802</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=421802</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE <br />
Contact: <br />
Kelli Baxter, Deputy  Executive Director, COO<br />
703-234-4088 | <a href="mailto:kbaxter@les.org">kbaxter@les.org</a></strong></p>
<strong>
</strong>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Jim  McCarthy To Receive Licensing Executives Society's (U.S.A. and Canada) Highest Honor, the President's Exemplary Service  Award, at the LES Annual Meeting in Boston</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>For Outstanding Volunteer Service to the  Organization, McCarthy to Be Honored  During the LES Annual Meeting, Oct. 15, 12:00-1:30 p.m., at the Boston Marriott  Copley </em></p>
<p>BOSTON – Oct.  10, 2018 – <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing Executives Society (<u>U.S.A</u>. and Canada), Inc. (LES)</a> today announced that <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/speaker/jim-mccarthy/">Jim McCarthy</a>, driving force and champion of  the LES Life Sciences Global Royalty Rate and Deal Terms Survey since its  inception, and Senior Vice-President, Corporate  &amp; Business Development, Rockwell Medical, Inc. will be presented with the  first-ever 2018 LES President's Exemplary Service Award. Established in 2018, the award is the highest  honor that LES can give to a member of the intellectual capital management  (ICM) community and honors an  LES volunteer who has made an outstanding contribution to the health, vibrancy,  and well-being of the Society. </p>
<ul>
    <li><strong><a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/register/">Register for the LES Annual  Meeting and hear McCarthy speak on the panel titled "Beyond 'Deals of  Distinction:' Lessons Learned and Best Practices: What Happened After the Ink  was Dry?" on Tues. Oct. 16.</a> </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>LES President and Chair Bill Elkington  will present the award to McCarthy at the Annual Meeting luncheon, on Oct. 15, from 12:00 to 1:30 p.m., at the  Boston Marriott Copley. </p>
<p>"In my view and <u>in</u> the view of many in our Society, Jim is one of the truly spectacular volunteers  in LES, and we are deeply grateful that he has chosen and continues to choose  this community to make his own," said Elkington. "He was the motivating force  in the original development and coordination of the LES Global Life Sciences Royalty  Rate and Deal Terms Survey, a survey that is invaluable to licensing people and  intellectual capital management people around the world. His tireless work to  improve the practice of licensing and intellectual capital management by supporting  our fellow members and society at large  makes Jim the embodiment of the LES promise and commitment."</p>
<p>McCarthy was  instrumental in spearheading the LES "Life Sciences Global Royalty Rate and  Deal Terms Survey," a definitive reference point for establishing royalty rates  in licensing transactions large and small worldwide.&nbsp; </p>
<p>In  addition to decades of contribution to LES, McCarthy has  over 30 years of direct life sciences professional experience. His background  includes a 25-year career with Bristol-Myers Squibb and Eli Lilly &amp; Company  and more than 20 years in international  corporate business development and licensing roles. These efforts included  projects and deals in over 30 countries with over 80 completed agreements  across a range of transactions. In recent years, he has been assisting small  and emerging life science companies to leverage their IP assets with strategic  and commercial planning, venture financing, commercial  initiatives and deal support on a global basis. </p>
<p>A Vietnam infantry veteran and Certified Licensing Professional  (CLP), McCarthy received his Masters of Business Administration from Indiana  University and his a Bachelor of Science in Physical Therapy from SUNY Upstate  Medical Center.</p>
<p><strong>About Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</strong><br />
Established  in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a  professional society of 3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial  development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection  and management of intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management  standards development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business  model innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists, engineers, IP valuation  experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition  experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain  managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members  represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such as  government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating  companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade  associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society  International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 10,000  members in 90 countries. <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">  ###</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Louise Levien To Receive 2018 Frank Barnes Mentor Award from the LES at Annual Meeting in Boston</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=420764</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=420764</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Kelli  Baxter<br />
Deputy Executive Director, COO<br />
kbaxter@les.org<br />
703-234-4088</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Louise Levien To Receive 2018 Frank Barnes Mentor Award from the Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) at  Annual Meeting in Boston</h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>For  Outstanding Work as Mentor in The Field of Licensing, Levien Will Be Honored During the Award Celebration, Oct. 15,  7:30-10:00 p.m., at the Boston Marriott Copley </em></p>
<p><strong>BOSTON</strong>—Oct. 3, 2018-- The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) today announced that it has selected <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/trusteebios#levien">Louise Levien, Ph.D., CLP,</a> a  member of the LES Board of Directors and the LES Director of Local Chapters  West, as the recipient of the <a href="https://www.lesusacanada.org/page/FrankBarnesAward">2018 LES Frank Barnes Mentor Award</a>. Levien's  substantial contributions to the field of licensing through mentorship make her  deserving of one of the highest honors that LES can give to a member of the licensing  community. Established in 2000 by LES to memorialize Barnes' contributions to  the field of licensing, the award is presented annually to one LES member who has dedicated considerable time and energy to  mentoring fellow licensing professionals.</p>
<p>While  maintaining an active role in LES as Houston Chapter Chair, a course instructor,  and on the Board of Directors, Levien has mentored many in the licensing field  in addition to speaking at local, national and international events. She currently  serves as a volunteer mentor for MD  Anderson's Venture Mentoring Service (VMS Houston) and recently served as the  mentor for an MD Anderson team at the NSF  I-CorpsTM 2018 Spring Bay Area Cohort.</p>
<p> Levien will be honored at the Society's  Monday evening <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/session/frank-barnes-award-presentation-evening-celebration/">LES  Supper Club and Frank Barnes Award Celebration</a> Oct. 15,  from 7:30-10:00 p.m., at the Boston Marriott Copley.  All are invited to register and attend.</p>
<ul>
    <li><a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/register/">Register  to attend the LES Annual Meeting</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>"This  year's award selection committee is pleased to present Louise with the 2018 LES  Frank Barnes Mentor Award. Louise displays the passion and drive to inspire and  encourage further innovation in the licensing sector. Additionally, I have  known Louise for many years and she has always been a trusted advisor and mentor  for me," said Don Drinkwater, chair of the Frank Barnes Award Committee, former  LES Board of Directors member and past president of the LES Foundation. "In  addition to embodying many of Mr. Barnes'  honorable mentor qualities, her service  to her LES chapter is truly unmatched and she is, therefore, the perfect  recipient. Congratulations to Dr. Levien." </p>
<p>  Before her retirement in  2017, Levien was  a member of ExxonMobil Upstream Research Company's Commercial, Intellectual  Property and Licensing group. Here, she  was responsible for IP processes, negotiating agreements and ensuring IP  terms were consistent with the business' needs in sponsored research and  licensing agreements. Much of her efforts made her the link between the  scientists and attorneys, mentoring both on the others' constraints.  Prior to this assignment, Levien worked as a  scientist and supervisor as well as a planner, where she developed several research management systems,  including one to manage ExxonMobil's  entire upstream research program.  A  Certified Licensing Professional (CLP) and the inventor of two patents, she  also holds an ScB in Geological Sciences  from Brown University and master's and doctoral  degrees in Geochemistry from Stony Brook University.</p>
<p><strong>About  Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.</strong><br />
Established in 1965,  Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional  society of 3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and  orderly transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of  intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards  development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model  innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists, engineers, IP valuation  experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition  experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain  managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members  represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such as government  laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating companies,  regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade associations. LES  is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc.  (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 10,000 members in 90  countries. <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> ###</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 3 Oct 2018 15:46:53 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) Brings Together World-Renowned Speakers</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=418966</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=418966</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</strong><br />
Kelli  Baxter<br />
Deputy Executive Director, COO<br />
kbaxter@les.org<br />
703-234-4088</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) Brings  Together World-Renowned Speakers to Highlight the State of Innovation at Annual  Meeting in Boston Oct. 14-17</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>IP professionals and business  leaders will benefit from a dynamic program that includes a historical look the evolution of patents and IP  in Boston to professional development, networking opportunities, and fun!</em></p>
<p><strong>BOSTON</strong>—September 20, 2018—The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A.  and Canada) today announced additional speakers and topics for its<a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/"> 2018  Annual Meeting</a>, held  in Boston, the birthplace of innovation, from Oct. 14-17, 2018, at the Boston Marriott  Copley Place. The highly-anticipated, three-day event is expected to  convene more than 500 executives and feature a speaker line-up of notable  business leaders and members of the IP, ICM and standards communities.  Registration and conference information is  available at <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18">www.lesmeetings.org/am18</a>. </p>
<ul>
    <li><strong><a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/register/">Special  discounted promotions ending soon—register now!</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<p>This year's meeting will build upon the  IP innovation theme, including an opening plenary and fireside chat entitled "<a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/session/opening-plenary-fireside-chat/">Advancing  Innovation Through A Renewal Of Trust</a>." Featured plenary speakers will explore the state of innovation and  competitiveness in America, and will include Bill Elkington, LES President and  Chair, Senior Director, IP Management, Rockwell Collins; Andrei Iancu, Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO);  and Dr. Walter G. Copan,  Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology and  Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST).</p>
<p>"Innovation is the principal  source of differentiated and defensible advantage for operating companies," said LES President and Chair Bill Elkington. "LES' vision is to connect and inspire the broad diversity of people  involved in IP, intellectual capital  management and standards development by providing them with lively and engaging  content, thought-provoking collegial discussions, beneficial best practices, and a comprehensive executive-quality  curriculum. That is what we plan to achieve this, and every year, at our Annual  Meeting."</p>
<p>The LES 2018 Annual Meeting <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/schedule-at-a-glance/">sessions and  educational panel</a> topics will explore the development and protection  of IP commerce, intellectual capital management and the LES Standards  Initiative. Highlights of the sessions include: </p>
<ul>
    <li>Funding  Startups – The Boston Perspective</li>
    <li>Setting  Standards for Licensing</li>
    <li>The  Joint Chiefs' Guide to Preparing for Patent War </li>
    <li>Navigating  Standard Essential Patents Issues Through International Waters </li>
    <li>Increasing  ROI for Government-Funded Research</li>
    <li>Advanced  Telecommunications Licensing, 4G, 5G and  LTE for Automobiles</li>
    <li>2018  Tax Consequences: Coordination of IP Monetization and Tax Planning</li>
    <li>Life  Sciences Partnering Performance and Reputation Survey Results</li>
    <li>Maximizing  IP Value and Minimizing Risk in M&amp;A Transactions</li>
</ul>
<p>LES would like to give special  thanks to its <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/sponsors/">2018 Annual Meeting sponsors</a>.&nbsp; The Annual Meeting experience can be started  early by downloading the Annual Meeting App. The App provides access to the  schedule, speakers, options to arrange one-on-one meetings, and more. The app can  be downloaded in the Apple  App or Google Play Store using the passphrase <strong>LESAM18</strong>. For more information about the conference, sponsorships or registration, visit <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18">www.lesmeetings.org/am18</a>. </p>
<p><strong>About Licensing Executives Society  (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.:</strong> <br />
Established in 1965, Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES) is a professional society of  3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly  transfer of intellectual property rights; protection and management of  intellectual capital; and intellectual capital management standards  development. LES members are accountants, business leaders, business model  innovators, consultants, deal-makers, economists, engineers, IP valuation  experts, lawyers, licensing executives, lobbyists, merger and acquisition  experts, public policy leaders, scientists, strategic planners, supply chain  managers, tax specialists, and technology transfer specialists. These members  represent innovation-centered enterprises of all sizes and kinds—such as  government laboratories, professional services firms, universities, operating  companies, regulatory authorities, licensing specialty firms, and trade  associations. LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society  International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing 10,000  members in 90 countries. <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">  ### </p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Licensing Executives Society Honors 14th Annual Deals of Distinction™ Award Winners at Annual Mtg</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=415750</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=415750</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: center;"><i><span>Recognized for Outstanding Achievements in the Field of Licensing Business Deals, LES Members to be Honored at LES 2018 Annual Meeting Awards Ceremony at Boston Marriott Copley Place&nbsp;</span></i></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: center;"><i><span>&nbsp;</span></i></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: left;">RESTON, VA—August 27, 2018—<a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/">The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A and Canada), Inc. (LES)</a> today announced it will honor LES member companies in five industry sectors with its Deals of Distinction™ Award. The annual program is exclusively for outstanding IP-based business deals by LES members undertaken in the past year. Now in its fourteenth year, the Deals of Distinction Awards™ are presented to the best deals in the Chemicals, Energy, Environment &amp; Materials (CEEM); High Technology (HTS); Industry University-Government Interface (IUGI); Life Sciences; and Consumer Products Sectors.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: left;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span>Award recipients will be honored at a ceremony during <span><a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/">LES’ Annual Meeting</a></span> Award Luncheon on Monday, October 15, 2018 at 12:00 p.m. at the Boston Marriott Copley Place.</span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span><br />
</span></p>
<p><span>“In today’s global economy, commercialization of intellectual property has the opportunity to drive growth across all business sectors, from traditional business products to non-core product technologies. This year’s award winners highlight LES member achievements across our current five sectors. Each recipient has made tremendous innovations within the licensing industry and we are proud to honor their success,” said LES CEO Kimberly S. Chotkowski. “From&nbsp;October 14-17, at our Annual Meeting in Boston, we look forward to a variety of ways to celebrate these deals and to hear from our members and speakers about the variety of topics impacting the Intellectual Capital Community. I offer a special thank you to the Deals of Distinction™ Award committee for highlighting the continued achievements of our LES members.”</span></p>
<p><span><br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span>This year’s award recipients from the following sectors will honored and will share details about their winning deals at the Award Luncheon:</span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span><br />
</span></p>
<ul>
    <li><b><span>Chemicals, Energy, Environment &amp; Materials (CEEM) Sector</span></b><span>: </span><span>Lightbridge Corp. (U.S.), Framatome, S.A. (France), and Framatome, Inc. (U.S.)—<i> Enfission Joint Venture between Lightbridge and Framatome Formed to Commercialize a Game-Changing Nuclear Fuel Technology</i></span><span style="color: black;"></span></li>
    <li style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><b><span>High Technology Sector (HTS)</span></b><span>:</span><span> Blockstack<i>—Blockstack’s $50 Million Initial Coin Offering (ICO)</i></span></li>
    <li style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><b><span>Industry-University-Government Interface (IUGI) Sector</span></b><span>: </span><span>The National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, part of the </span><span>National Institutes of Health and Serum Institute of India, Pvt. Ltd.<i>—</i><span style="color: #666666;"> <i>ROTASIIL®, a low-cost, temperature tolerant rotavirus vaccine for developing countries</i></span></span></li>
    <li style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><b><span>Life Sciences Sector</span></b><span>: Pieris Pharmaceuticals and Astra Zeneca—<i>Worldwide</i></span><i><span style="color: #666666;"> Preclinical Alliance for Antibody Mimics to Treat Respiratory Diseases</span></i></li>
    <li><i><span>&nbsp;</span></i><b><span>Consumer Products Sector:</span></b><span> Ericsson and Micromax—<i>Ericsson-Micromax Global Standards Essential Patent License Agreement</i></span></li>
</ul>
<p><span><i>&nbsp;</i></span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span style="color: #666666;">All LES members attending the Annual Meeting are invited to attend the Award Luncheon. Additional information about the LES 2018 Annual Meeting and registration instructions can be found at&nbsp;</span><a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am18/">www.lesmeetings.org/am18/</a><span style="color: black;">. <span style="color: #666666;">Previous honorees&nbsp;and award-winning deals can be found at&nbsp;<span class="apple-converted-space"></span></span></span><a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/?dda">www.lesusacanada.org/?dda</a><span style="color: black;">.</span><br />
</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><strong><span>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.:</span></strong><strong></strong></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span><em>Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. [LES (U.S.A. and Canada)] is the industry leader for a professional society of over 3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property. LES (U.S.A. and Canada) members are comprised&nbsp;of accountants, consultants, lawyers, engineers, executives, and scientists. These members represent innovation-oriented enterprises of all sizes—such as government laboratories, professional services firms, global corporations and universities. LES (U.S.A. and Canada) is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing over 10,000 members in 90 countries. <span><a href="www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a></span></em></span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span><em><span>&nbsp;</span></em></span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: left;"><b><span>MEDIA CONTACT<br />
</span></b>Kelli Baxter<br />
Deputy Executive Director, COO<br />
kbaxter@les.org<br />
703-234-4088</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 14:43:39 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Licensing Executives Society Concerned By Further Decline in US Patent System</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=387151</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=387151</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>RESTON, VA, FEBRUARY 15, 2018</strong> - The Licensing Executives Society
(USA and Canada), Inc. (LES) is deeply concerned by recent evidence of further  decline in the effectiveness of the U.S. patent system. On February 8th, the  U.S. Chamber of Commerce Global Innovation Policy Center released the 6th  edition of its International IP Index. The Index finds that the U.S. patent  system has fallen to 12th place in the world. It's lowest ranking in the six  years of the history of the Index. This comes after last year's surprising fall  from first to 10th place, tied with Hungary.</p>
<p> The U.S. Chamber attributes the  decline to a "growing level of uncertainty for innovators, particularly in  relation to patent protection and technology licensing." The Index  specifically cites uncertainties resulting from inconsistent interpretation of  Supreme Court attempts to define patent-eligible subject matter by lower courts  and the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office. The Index further cites challenges  innovators face in post-grant opposition proceedings, which "involve a  great deal of cost and lack of predictability for patent owners compared with  other post-grant opposition systems."</p>
<p>  According to LES Past President  Brian O'Shaughnessy, "This is all the more disconcerting as LES and its  innovation-oriented members have long since pointed to these challenges as  compromising our patent system, devaluing innovation, and suppressing new  business formation. As goes our patent system, so goes our economy."</p>
<p>  LES CEO, Kim Chotkowski adds  "The cause for concern is still greater in view of Bloomberg's recent  report finding that the U.S. has fallen out of the world's top ten  innovation-oriented economies, citing similar challenges. Clearly, corrective  measures are needed."</p>
<p>  LES supports legislative and  industry efforts to restore the U.S. patent system to its former preeminence.  Among these are bills that would remedy the very challenges cited by the Index,  including the STRONGER Patents Act (S. 1390). Industry self-regulation will  also restore the vitality of our patent and licensing system. Through its  Standards Initiative, LES has created a forum, open to all innovation-oriented  enterprises, for developing consensus standards in IP-oriented business  processes and behavior. These standards will streamline licensing and IP commercialization,  and reduce the costs and uncertainties that have contributed to the decline of  our patent system.</p>
<p><strong><em>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.:</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Established in 1965, the Licensing Executives Society, LES, has been a leading association for professionals in the business of intellectual property. Our members evaluate, protect, acquire, sell, license, and enforce IP rights. Our business executives, lawyers, accountants, engineers, scientists, and other experts come from a wide array of startups, multinational corporations, universities, government laboratories, law firms, valuation firms, and other consultancies. Nearly 3000 IP transaction professionals belong to LES (U.S.A. and Canada), and together with 32 other national and regional societies form the membership of the Licensing Executives Society International, totaling nearly 10,000 IP transaction professionals in 90 countries.</em><a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/" target="_blank"><em>www.lesusacanada.org</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><strong>MEDIA CONTACT</strong><br />
Kim Chotkowski<br />
Chief Executive Officer<br />
Phone: (484) 459-1454<br />
Email address: <a href="mailto:kchotkowski@les.org">kchotkowski@les.org</a></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 02:05:14 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>New LES (U.S.A. and Canada) Board of Directors to Begin Term  at LES 2017 Annual Meeting in Chicago</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=371504</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=371504</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h2 align="center">New LES (U.S.A. and Canada) Board of  Directors to Begin Term 
	at LES 2017 Annual Meeting in Chicago</h2>
<p>Chicago, IL. (October 24, 2017) The Licensing  Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. is pleased to announce the  2017-2018 Board of Directors. They will begin their leadership roles during the  LES 2017 Annual Meeting in Chicago, Illinois.   See photos and full biographies <a href="http://c.ymcdn.com/sites/www.lesusacanada.org/resource/resmgr/docs/17-18_Bios.pdf" target="_blank">here</a> and learn more about the Annual Meeting at <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am17">http://www.lesmeetings.org/am17</a>.  Congratulations to the following  newly elected leaders: </p>
<ul>
  <li>President and Chair of the Board William Elkington</li>
  <li>President-Elect and Chair-Elect of the Board -  Robert Held</li>
  <li>Immediate Past-President and Past-Chair of the Board  - Brian O’Shaughnessy</li>
  <li>Secretary - Kevin Spivak</li>
  <li>Treasurer - Mike Pellegrino</li>
  <li>Counsel - Paul A. Roberts</li>
  <li>Vice President of Membership, Communications, and  Technology - Ida Shum</li>
  <li>Senior Vice President of Meeting, Education, and  Strategic Alliances - Gary Fedorochko</li>
  <li>Vice President  International - Jim Bratton </li>
  <li>Vice President  of Public Policy and Standards - Rachel Kreppel</li>
  <li>Local Chapters  East Director - Annie Gauthier</li>
  <li>Local Chapters  West Director - Louise Levien</li>
  <li>Director of  Membership & Member Engagement - Annmarie Meike</li>
  <li>Director of  Communications & Publications - Gillian Fenton</li>
  <li>Director  Meetings – Scott Williams </li>
  <li>Director of  Education - Matthew McNeill</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>LES Chief Executive Officer Kim Chotkowski noted, “I  look forward to working with this new slate of dedicated volunteers who have  made significant contributions to the IP industry and our U.S.A. and Canada  Society.” </p>
<p><strong><em>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A.  and Canada), Inc.:</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Established in 1965, the Licensing  Executives Society, LES, has been a leading association for professionals in  the business of intellectual property. Our members evaluate, protect, acquire,  sell, license, and enforce IP rights. Our business executives, lawyers,  accountants, engineers, scientists, and other experts come from a wide array of  startups, multinational corporations, universities, government laboratories,  law firms, valuation firms, and other consultancies. Nearly 3000 IP transaction  professionals belong to LES (U.S.A. and Canada), and together with 32 other  national and regional societies form the membership of the Licensing Executives  Society International, totaling nearly 10,000 IP transaction professionals in  90 countries.</em><a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/" target="_blank"><em>www.lesusacanada.org</em></a><em>. </em></p>
 <p> <strong>MEDIA CONTACT</strong><br>
  Kelli  Baxter <br>
  Deputy  Executive Director, COO <br>
  kbaxter@les.org <br>
  (703)  234-4088</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) To Release High Technology Royalty Rate Survey</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=370896</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=370896</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<table border="0" class="ViewTable1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="100%" style="width: 743px; margin: 20px 0px; border: 0px; border-spacing: 0px;">
    <tbody>
        <tr>
            <td style="padding: 5px; border: 0px; text-align: left;">
            <p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 20px;"><span><strong>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</strong></span></p>
            <h4 style="text-align: center;">Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada) To Release High Technology Royalty Rate Survey <br />
            </h4>
            <p style="color: #000000; margin: 0px 0px 0.0001pt; text-align: center;"><span>&nbsp;</span></p>
            <p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span>VIRGINIA, October 19, 2017 –<b>The Licensing Executives Society, U.S.A. &amp; Canada (“LES”) will release its High Technology Royalty Rate and Deal Terms Survey at the 2017 Annual Meeting in Chicago, October 22-25, 2017.&nbsp; </b>High technology intellectual property transactions support a great deal of economic activity in the USA &amp; Canada, and the world over.&nbsp; Consolidated, meaningful data on how those deals are constructed has been generally unavailable. &nbsp;In 2011, the LES Royalty Rate and Deal Terms Surveys covering High Technology deals changed all that.&nbsp; LES has now conducted its third iteration of this valuable, worldwide survey.&nbsp; The latest survey provides data on 155 completed deals submitted by 70 entities. </span></p>
            <p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span>&nbsp;</span></p>
            <p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><b><span>“<i>These surveys represent the most sought-after licensing industry information that the Society offers</i>”</span></b><span>, said Bob Held, Survey Co-Chair, and President-Elect and Chair-Elect nominee of the Board of the Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. for 2018-2019.<br />
            <br />
            </span></p>
            <p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span>Across the High Technology industry, which relies heavily on successful collaborations, alliances and deal-making, there has been a major gap in deal data to help inform, teach and guide professionals in negotiations.&nbsp; LES has addressed this gap in the High Technology industry with its wide-ranging, in-depth ‘Royalty Rate and Deal Terms Survey.’ The Society has completed similar surveys looking at deal terms and royalty rate data in the life sciences/health care sector, and in the chemicals, energy, environment, and materials sector.</span></p>
            <p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span>&nbsp;</span></p>
            <p><span>The data gathered covers deals concluded since January 2014, and comes from a variety of operating companies, academic institutions, government labs, as well as licensing experts, lawyers, and other licensing organizations worldwide.&nbsp; The survey looks at fixed percentage and per unit royalties, tiered royalties, and financial and non- financial components included in those deals.&nbsp; </span></p>
            <p><span>The aggregate survey data will be analyzed by the LES Survey Committee, and key findings and highlights will be presented at the LES Annual Meeting in Chicago on Wednesday, October 25, 2017 at 2:00 pm.&nbsp; LES expects over 600 delegates at this years’ Annual Meeting, representing the leading lights in intellectual capital management and technology licensing.&nbsp; LES is a non-profit, non-partisan, open, and inclusive professional society; and its meetings are open to all.&nbsp; Registration and hotel information is available at: <a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am17/">http://www.lesmeetings.org/am17/</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></p>
            <p><span>The comprehensive High-Tech Royalty Rate and Deal Terms Survey Report, including comprehensive survey findings and related analysis, will be available as a member benefit to all LES members (<a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/">www.lesusacanada.org</a>).&nbsp; The Survey Report will be available to the general public for a fee. </span></p>
            <p><span>The survey itself was conducted by the independent research firm of Vault Consulting to ensure confidentiality of the participants.&nbsp; The Survey initiative was co-chaired by industry experts Lewis Stark, CPA/CFE and Bob Held, MBA/CLP.&nbsp; Lewis, Bob and economist Dr. Jack Lu, CFA, and licensing expert Joe Daniele, CLP, will be presenting the initial findings in Chicago.</span></p>
            <p><span>For more information on the Royalty Rate and Deal Terms surveys or the annual meeting, please visit <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/">www.lesusacanada.org</a> or call (703) 234-4058.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
            <p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 0.0001pt;"><span></span><em><br />
            <br />
            About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.:</em></p>
            <p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 0.0001pt;"><em>&nbsp;</em><br />
            </p>
            <p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 20px;"><em>Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. [LES (U.S.A. and Canada)] is the industry leader for a professional society of over 3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property. LES (U.S.A. and Canada) members are comprisedof accountants, consultants, lawyers, engineers, executives, and scientists. These members represent innovation-oriented enterprises of all sizes—such as government laboratories, professional services firms, global corporations and universities. LES (U.S.A. and Canada) is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing over 10,000 members in 90 countries.<a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/" style="background: 0px 0px;">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.</em></p>
            <p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 20px; text-align: center;">###</p>
            <p style="color: #000000; margin: 0px 0px 0.0001pt;"><span>MEDIA CONTACT</span><br />
            Kelli Baxter<br />
            Deputy Executive Director, COO<br />
            <a href="mailto:kbaxter@les.org" style="background: 0px 0px;">kbaxter@les.org</a><br />
            703-234-4088</p>
            </td>
        </tr>
    </tbody>
</table>
<a name="comments"></a>
<div style="padding: 10px 0px 0px 3px;"><input class="FormButton" type="button" name="btnLoginToComment" value="Add Comment" style="color: #515151; border-color: #d8d8d8;" /></div>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 04:41:56 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Distinguished BioPharmaceuticals Mentor to be Recognized at the  LES 2017 Annual Meeting in Chicago</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=370110</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=370110</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE</strong></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;">Distinguished BioPharmaceuticals Mentor to be Recognized at the LES 2017 Annual Meeting in Chicago</h4>
<p style="color: #000000; margin: 0px 0px 0.0001pt; text-align: center;"><span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span>Reston, Va. (October 16, 2017)&nbsp;On Monday, October 23, 2017, &nbsp;the Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. will recognize Frank&nbsp;Barnes&nbsp;Mentor Award recipient Bill Mattson, a longtime LES (U.S.A. and Canada) member and retired leader in biopharmaceuticals. Mattson will be presented this award during the LES 2017 Annual Meeting’s gala reception and dinner at the Chicago Marriott Downtown Magnificent Mile.</span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span>
The Frank&nbsp;Barnes&nbsp;Mentor Award was established to memorialize its namesakes’ vast mentorship contributions and recognize those who have advised others in their field.&nbsp;During a long career that has spanned billions in major transactions and years with the top names in healthcare, Mattson is being honored for the time and energy he has spent mentoring his peers. He previously served on the Board of Trustees for the St. Louis College of Pharmacy and has&nbsp;45 years of experience with Abbott Labs, Monsanto/Searle Pharmaceuticals, The Mattson Jack Group, and Linden Capital.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span><br />
The last five Frank&nbsp;Barnes&nbsp;Mentor Award recipients were Ed Saltzman of Defined Heath (2016), Lawrence J. Udell of the California Invention Center (2015), John G. Poulos of AbbVie (2014), Don Drinkwater of the Bose Corporation (2013), and Pam Demain of Merck (2012).&nbsp;A full list of previous honorees and additional information can be found at&nbsp;</span><span><a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/link.asp?e=shouchins@les.org&amp;job=3113046&amp;ymlink=168815548&amp;finalurl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Elesfoundation%2Eorg%2Fawards%2Findex%2Ehtml" target="_blank"><span>http://www.lesfoundation.org/awards</span></a></span><span>.</span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span><br />
Prior to his time as Operating Partner at Linden Capital, Mattson cofounded The Mattson Jack Group and helped to build the business to 110 employees. The consulting firm was later acquired by the WPP Group (now Kantar Health). Mattson began his career working in finance at Abbott Labs, where his passion for biopharmaceuticals would lead him to general management roles around the world. The award recipient earned a Master in Business Administration from Loyola University and a Bachelor of Science in Accounting from Bradley University.</span></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span><br />
The Frank&nbsp;Barnes&nbsp;Mentor Award presentation will be one of the highlights of the “Licensing in Blues Alley” Gala Reception and "Chicago, Chicago, That Kind of a Town” Gala Dinner. Attendees are invited to go&nbsp;back to the heart of music in Chicago by wearing some 1920s-inspired, after-five (semi-formal) style for a night of nostalgic fun.&nbsp;This award is presented annually and is&nbsp;part of the LES 2017 Annual Meeting in Chicago, Illinois (Sunday, October 22 to Wednesday, October 25, 2017). Learn more at&nbsp;</span><span><a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/link.asp?e=shouchins@les.org&amp;job=3113046&amp;ymlink=168815548&amp;finalurl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Elesmeetings%2Eorg%2Fam17%2F" target="_blank"><span>www.lesmeetings.org/am17/</span></a></span><span>.</span></p>
<p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 20px;"><em><br />
<br />
About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc.:</em><br />
<strong></strong></p>
<p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 20px;"><em>Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. [LES (U.S.A. and Canada)] is the industry leader for a professional society of over 3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property. LES (U.S.A. and Canada) members are comprised&nbsp;of accountants, consultants, lawyers, engineers, executives, and scientists. These members represent innovation-oriented enterprises of all sizes—such as government laboratories, professional services firms, global corporations and universities. LES (U.S.A. and Canada) is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has 32 sister societies representing over 10,000 members in 90 countries.<a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/" style="background: 0px 0px;">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.</em></p>
<p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 20px; text-align: center;">###</p>
<p style="color: #000000; margin: 0px 0px 0.0001pt;"><span>MEDIA CONTACT</span><br />
Kelli Baxter<br />
Deputy Executive Director, COO<br />
<a href="mailto:kbaxter@les.org" style="background: 0px 0px;">kbaxter@les.org</a><br />
703-234-4088</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 20:16:48 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>13th Annual Deals of Distinction™ Award Winners to be Recognized in Chicago</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=369014</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=369014</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h4 style="text-align: center;">13<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;Annual Deals of Distinction™ Award Winners to be Recognized in Chicago</h4>
<p style="color: #000000; margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: center;"><i>LES (U.S.A. and Canada) to honor recipients at LES 2017 Annual Meeting&nbsp;
(October 22-25, 2017)</i></p>
<p style="color: #000000; margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-align: center;"><span>&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>Reston,  Va. (October 10, 2017) Four of the year’s most creative and  innovative intellectual property (IP) deals have been named Deals of  Distinction™ by the Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A and Canada), Inc. and  will be recognized at their Annual Business Meeting and Luncheon on Monday,  October 23, 2017 at 12:15 pm. </p>
<p>“These  deals represent outstanding industry achievements and technologies that both  strengthen international commerce and improve our global community,” said LES  (U.S.A. and Canada) CEO Kimberly S. Chotkowski.&nbsp; </p>
<p>Award  recipients from the following LES (U.S.A. and Canada) sectors will honored and  will share details about their winning deals at the Chicago Marriott Magnificent  Mile's 7th floor Grand Ballroom:</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Chemicals, Energy, Environment &amp; Materials (CEEM) Sector</strong>: ExxonMobil Upstream Research Company and Pohang Iron &amp;  Steel Company (POSCO)<em>—High Manganese  Steel Slurry Pipe License and Commercialization</em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
    <li><strong>High Technology  Sector (HTS)</strong>:  AT&amp;T and Uber Technologies - <em>AT&amp;T's  Patent Sale to Uber</em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Industry-University-Government  Interface (IUGI) Sector</strong>: AbbVie, Inc., Biogen, and National Institutes of Health  (NIH-US)<em> - Zinbryta® for Treatment of Relapsing  Multiple Sclerosis</em></li>
</ul>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Life Sciences Sector</strong>:  Xencor, Inc. and Novartis - <em>Preclinical  Immuno-Oncology Bispecific Antibody Alliance</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Previous  honorees&nbsp;and award-winning deals can be found at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org/?dda">www.lesusacanada.org/?dda</a>. Additional information  about the LES 2017 Annual Meeting can be found at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.lesmeetings.org/am17/">www.lesmeetings.org/am17/</a>. </p>
<p><strong><em>About Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and  Canada), Inc.:</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Established in 1965, Licensing Executives Society  (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. [LES (U.S.A. and Canada)] is the industry leader for a  professional society of over 3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial  development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property. LES (U.S.A. and  Canada) members are comprised&nbsp;of accountants, consultants, lawyers, engineers,  executives, and scientists. These members represent innovation-oriented  enterprises of all sizes—such as government laboratories, professional services  firms, global corporations and universities. LES (U.S.A. and Canada) is a  member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI),  which has 32 sister societies representing over 10,000 members in 90 countries.  <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">###</p>
<p style="color: #000000; margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><strong>MEDIA CONTACT</strong><br />
Kelli  Baxter<br />
Deputy  Executive Director, COO<br />
<a href="mailto:kbaxter@les.org">kbaxter@les.org</a><br />
703-234-4088</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LES Nominates Mr. Robert Held, President-Elect, 2018</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=344740</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=344740</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h4>The Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. Nominates Mr. Robert Held, President-Elect, 2018</h4>
<p><strong><img alt="" src="https://members.lesusacanada.org/resource/resmgr/bot/BHeldPhoto.jpg" style="border:10px solid #ffffff;width: 210px; height: 239px; float: left;" />Wednesday, May 10, 2017 - </strong>Mr. Robert (Bob) Held is officially nominated as President and Chair-Elect of the Board of the Licensing Executives Society (U.S.A. and Canada), Inc. (LES). &nbsp;If elected, his one-year term would commence at the 2018 LES Annual Meeting in Boston, Massachusetts. Bob is currently Regional Vice President for Policy, Standards, International &amp; Strategic Planning on the LES Board of Directors.<br />
<br />
Bob has been active in LES since 1998, and during that time &nbsp;he has occupied many roles including Chair of the Aerospace and Transportation Subcommittee of the High Tech Sector (HTS) 2006-2007; Secretary, Vice-Chair and Chair of the HTS 2011-2014, Co-Chair and co-author of the HTS Royalty Rate and Deal Terms Surveys for 2011, 2014 and 2017; &nbsp;Program Chair for the 2012 LES Annual Meeting; Program Chair for the 2013 LES Annual Meeting, and LES Vice President for Education on the LES Board of Directors 2014-2016.<br />
<br />
In addition to filling various roles in LES, Bob has presented on a variety of intellectual property (IP) topics around the world, and frequently appears as faculty in LES education programs.<br />
<br />
Bob is Founder and President of Held Intellectual Property, LLC, an intellectual property consulting and services firm leveraging Bob's 30+ years in business and 20 years in IP. He recently served as the Vice President of Intellectual Asset Management for TeleCommunication Systems, Inc. (TCS) in Annapolis, Maryland. &nbsp;All assets of TCS were acquired in February 2016. &nbsp;Immediately prior to joining TCS, Bob worked for Northrop Grumman Corporation, Electronic Systems Sector from 2003-2011 as the Director of the IP &amp; Strategic Technology Agreements business unit; and from 1998-2003 he worked at the IP firm British Technology Group (BTG) International as the Associate Vice President of Licensing.<br />
<br />
Bob has been a Certified Licensing Professional (CLP) since 2008 and was named to the "IAM Strategy 300-The World's Leading IP Strategists" in 2015, 2016 and 2017. &nbsp;He received his Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering degree from Villanova University and his MBA from Drexel University's LeBow College of Business.<br />
<br />
Visit <a href="www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a> for more information on LES (USA &amp; Canada), its Board of Directors, meetings and other activities.</p>
<p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 20px; text-align: center;"># # #</p>
<p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 20px;"><span><strong>About LES (USA &amp; Canada), Inc.:</strong></span>&nbsp;Established in 1965, LES (USA &amp; Canada), Inc. is a professional society of nearly 3,000 members engaged in the creation, commercial development, and orderly transfer of intellectual property. &nbsp;LES members include business executives, lawyers, accountants, consultants, and scientists and engineers; and those members represent innovation-oriented enterprises of all sizes, professional services firms, universities, and government labs. &nbsp;LES is a member society of the Licensing Executives Society International, Inc. (LESI), which has more than 10,000 members worldwide among 32 sister societies representing 90 countries. For more information about LES, visit <a href="www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p style="color: #333333; margin: 0px 0px 20px;"><span><span><span><strong>Media Contact:</strong></span></span></span><span><span><br />
</span></span><span>Monique dela Cruz</span><br />
<span>Communications Manager</span><br />
<span>mdelacruz@les.org</span><br />
<span>(703) 234-4062</span></p>
<div>&nbsp;</div>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 21:36:06 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
