<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>News &amp; Press</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/default.asp</link>
<description><![CDATA[  Read about recent events, essential information and the latest community news.  ]]></description>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 17:52:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Tue, 6 Oct 2020 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<copyright>Copyright &#xA9; 2020 Licensing Executives Society (LES)</copyright>
<atom:link href="https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news_rss.asp?cat=11034" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
<item>
<title>Granting or recording a security interest in a patent at the USPTO does not deprive the patent owner</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=526272</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=526272</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h2><strong>Granting or recording a security  interest in a patent at the USPTO does not deprive the patent owner of the  ability to enforce the patent</strong></h2>
<p>By <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/johnpaul/">John Paul</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/briankacedon/">Brian Kacedon</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/ceciliasanabria/">Cecilia Sanabria</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/en/professionals/anthony-d-del-monaco.html">Anthony D. Del Monaco</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/en/professionals/umber-aggarwal.html">Umber Aggarwal</a></p>
<p><strong>Edited by </strong><a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/johnpaul/">John  Paul</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/briankacedon/">Brian  Kacedon</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/en/professionals/anthony-d-del-monaco.html">Anthony Del Monaco</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/ceciliasanabria/">Cecilia  Sanabria</a></p>
<p>Abstract: A  patentee did not lose the ability to bring a patent infringement lawsuit when  it entered into a security interest agreement covering all of its intellectual  property and the agreement was recorded at the USPTO </p>
<p><strong>Background</strong> <br>
  Raffel,  a manufacturer of electronic controls for the seating, bedding and industrial marketplaces, entered into an “Intellectual  Property Security Agreement” with two different banks granting the banks a  security interest in all of its intellectual property. The banks filed notices  of their security interests with the USPTO. Shortly thereafter, Raffel sued Man  Wah for patent infringement and other causes of actions. In response, Man  Wah moved to dismiss Raffel’s patent infringement claims arguing that Raffel  lacked the right to sue for infringement because the security agreements  transferred title of Raffel’s intellectual property to the banks.</p>
<p> <strong>Trial Court’s Decision</strong> <br>
  Lenders take security interests in a debtor’s  intellectual property and other assets to protect themselves if the debtor  defaults on a loan. In some instances, the lender demands that the security  agreement transfer the ownership in the intellectual property until the loan is  repaid.</p>
<p> The  trial court found the act of granting a security interest in intellectual  property and recording that security interest at the USPTO did not transfer  title of the patents from Raffel to the banks, and, therefore, Raffel retained  the right to enforce the patents.</p>
<p>To  have the ability or “standing” to sue for patent infringement, an entity must  satisfy the requirements of the U.S. constitution as well as the patent  statute. To have constitutional standing, a plaintiff must possess exclusionary  rights in the patent such as the right to prevent others from making, using,  selling, or offering to sell the patented invention. Statutory standing further  requires that the plaintiff have “all substantial rights” to the asserted  patents through being the original patentee, an assignee, or an exclusive licensee  of all such rights. &nbsp;If an entity has  “exclusionary rights” in the patent but lacks “all substantial rights,” it typically  must join the owner of the patent in any infringement suit.</p>
<p>Man  Wah argued that Raffel’s grant of a security interest and the subsequent  recording of that security interest transferred title to the banks and thus,  deprived Raffel of “standing” to sue.&nbsp; In  support, Man Wah relied on a Supreme Court case from 1891, <em>Waterman v.  Mackenzie</em>, which supported the principle that recording a security interest  in patents was equivalent to transferring title. &nbsp;The court noted, however, that <em>Waterman</em> was decided prior to the enactment of the Uniform Commercial Code (“UCC”) in  1952, which fundamentally changed the way a security interest is perfected. After the enactment of the UCC in 1952,  transfer of title was unnecessary to perfect a security interest.</p>
<p> Man  Wah asserted that state UCC laws provide only one way for a party to perfect  security interests and are preempted by the Patent Act and <em>Waterman</em> when  they conflict. Specifically, Man Wah argued that, under the Patent Act and <em>Waterman</em>,  a security interest is created through transfer of the patent when it is  recorded at the USPTO. Man Wah asserted that this preempts perfecting a  security interest through the UCC which does not transfer title. The court  rejected the preemption argument citing numerous cases showing the Patent Act  does not address perfection in security interests, but only assignments of  title, and, thus, does not preempt state regulation of security interests in  patents.</p>
<p> In  looking at the actual agreements with the banks, the court confirmed that “[n]othing in the Intellectual Property  Security Agreements states that Raffel is assigning title of the patents to the  banks; rather, the agreements specifically state that Raffel is granting a ‘security  interest’ in its intellectual property.” Thus, Raffel never transferred title  and maintained standing. The court, therefore, denied the motion to  dismiss.</p>
<p> <strong>Strategy and Conclusion</strong> <br>
  A  party receiving a security interest in a patent may record the security  agreement with the USPTO to protect itself against and give notice to  subsequent bona fide purchasers or mortgagees. Standard security agreements  that do not include language assigning title of the patents, however, will not  prevent a patentee from bringing a patent infringement lawsuit. This case  demonstrates the value of drafting the security agreement in a way that does  not transfer ownership of intellectual property to the lender while the loan is  pending.&nbsp; </p>
<p>The <em>Raffel </em>decision can be found <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/images/content/3/1/v2/311072/Raffel-Systems-LLC-v.-Man-Wah-Holdings-Limited-Inc.pdf">here</a>.<strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Editors and Authors</strong><br>
  The editors and authors are  attorneys at Finnegan, Henderson, Farabow, Garrett &amp; Dunner, LLP.<br>
  <br>
  <em>This article  is for informational purposes and does not constitute legal advice.</em></p>
<em>The views expressed  do not necessarily reflect the views of LES or Finnegan.</em>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 6 Oct 2020 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>To avoid an allegation that a patent assignor is estopped from arguing that an asserted patent is </title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=526273</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=526273</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h2>To avoid an allegation that a  patent assignor is estopped from arguing that an asserted patent is invalid,  the assignor estoppel defense should be disclosed in a timely fashion or the  late disclosure should be substantially justified and harmless</h2>
<p>  By <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/johnpaul/">John Paul</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/briankacedon/">Brian Kacedon</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/ceciliasanabria/">Cecilia Sanabria</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/en/professionals/anthony-d-del-monaco.html">Anthony D. Del Monaco</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/en/professionals/amanda-e-stephenson.html">Amanda Stephenson</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>
<p>Edited by <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/johnpaul/">John Paul</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/briankacedon/">Brian Kacedon</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/ceciliasanabria/">Cecilia Sanabria</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/en/professionals/anthony-d-del-monaco.html">Anthony D. Del Monaco</a><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Abstract:  When deciding if a party should be precluded from asserting assignor estoppel  within two weeks of the close of fact discovery, a Massachusetts Court looked  to Federal Rules of Civil Procedure 26 and 37 to decide if the defense was  timely disclosed and, if not, whether the late disclosure was substantially  justified or harmless. The court held that the defense was timely disclosed  under Rule 26 and substantially justified and harmless under Rule 37.</p>
<p><strong>Background</strong><br>
  Abiomed  sought a declaratory judgment that its “Impella” line of intravascular blood  pumps did not infringe Maquet’s patent. (Abiomed initially filed declaratory  judgment on multiple Maquet patents, but currently only one patent at issue  remains.)</p>
<p> Maquet  counterclaimed that Abiomed infringed its patent, and Abiomed responded by arguing  that the asserted patent claims were invalid. <br>
  Maquet  then argued that Abiomed was barred from a defense that the claims were invalid  because of the assignor estoppel doctrine that prevents the assignor of a  patent from asserting that the patent is invalid.</p>
<p> The  parties had already filed motions for summary judgment on validity, where  Maquet argued that Abiomed is precluded from challenging the validity of  Maquet’s asserted claims.</p>
<p> Abiomed  filed a separate motion to (1) preclude Maquet from asserting an assignor estoppel  defense; (2) prevent Maquet from seeking additional discovery on its assignor estoppel  theory; and (3) strike Maquet’s letter to the court concerning the theory. The court  denied the motion.</p>
<p> <strong>The <em>Abiomed</em> Decision</strong> <br>
  The  court explained that assignor estoppel is an equitable remedy prohibiting an  assignor of a patent, such as an inventor or one in privity with an assignor,  such as an inventor’s employer, from challenging the validity of a patent when  the assignee asserts a patent infringement claim against the assignor or one in  privity with the assignor.</p>
<p> Dr.  Walid Abdoul-Hosn, a named inventor of the asserted patent, assigned the patent  to Maquet while he worked at Maquet. Dr. Abdoul-Hosn left Maquet and began  working for Abiomed in 2007, about a year after the patent was granted. Abiomed  first sold the allegedly infringing article, the Impella, in the U.S. in 2008.</p>
<p> Maquet  argued that Dr. Abdoul-Hosn was in privity with Abiomed because he helped  design the infringing elements of the Impella, and therefore assignor estoppel  should apply, preventing Abiomed from challenging the validity of the asserted  patent. The dispute here, however, did not involve the merits of the assignor estoppel  claim. Instead, the dispute centered on whether Maquet should be able to assert  assignor estoppel under Rules 26 and 37 of the Federal Rules of Civil  Procedure. The court held that Maquet did not violate Rule 26 and would not  have been precluded under Rule 37, allowing them to assert assignor estoppel.</p>
<p> Rule  26 requires a party to disclose the name, contact information, and knowledgeable  subjects of any witness likely to have discoverable information relating to its  claims or defenses and to supplement the disclosures, as necessary.</p>
<p> Maquet  disclosed Dr. Abdoul-Hosn on its initial and subsequent disclosures. Additionally,  four days after Dr. Abdoul-Hosn’s deposition, Maquet informed Abiomed by email that  it intended to assert assignor estoppel. On the last day of fact discovery,  Maquet supplemented an interrogatory response to include its assertion of  assignor estoppel. Therefore, the court held that Maquet did not violate Rule  26, timely disclosing Dr. Abdoul-Hosn and its assignor estoppel defense.</p>
<p> Even though the court  held that Maquet did not violate Rule 26, it went on to opine on the merits of  Rule 37.</p>
<p> Rule 37 states that a  witness and/or the information that they were to provide can be precluded if a  party violates Rule 26 unless the failure was substantially justified or  harmless. In this case, the court held that even if Maquet’s notice under Rule  26 was late, it would have been substantially justified and harmless. It would  have been substantially justified because Marquet learned of Dr. Abdoul-Hosn’s  involvement in the research, design, development, and manufacture of the Impella  during his deposition, just over two weeks from the close of fact discovery. It  was harmless because Abiomed would not have suffered significant prejudice from  the late disclosure. </p>
<p> Further, the court reasoned  that Abiomed was not significantly prejudiced because fact and expert discovery  was closed, Dr. Abdoul-Hosn had been deposed, Abiomed did not seek additional  discovery related to assignor estoppel, and Maquet’s motion to compel  additional discovery relating to assignor estoppel had been denied. Additionally,  Abiomed was able to cite substantial evidence refuting that it was in privity  with Dr. Abdoul-Hosn in its rebuttal to Marquet’s motion for summary judgment  on validity, which included its assignor estoppel claim. Thus, the court held  that even if Maquet had violated Rule 26, preclusion was not necessary under  Rule 37.</p>
<p> <strong>Strategy  and Conclusion</strong><br>
  To avoid allegations that the assignor  estoppel defense has been waived it is recommended to assert the defense as  soon as information indicates the defense is available.</p>
<p> <strong>Further Information<br>
</strong>The <em>Abiomed </em>decision can be found <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/images/content/3/1/v2/312542/ORDER-ON-ABIOMED-S-MOTION-TO-PRECLUDE-AND-FOR-A-PROTECTIVE-ORD.pdf">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Editors and Authors<br>
</strong> The authors are attorneys at  Finnegan, Henderson, Farabow, Garrett &amp; Dunner, LLP. </p>

<p><em>This  article is for informational purposes and does not constitute legal advice.</em><br>
  <em>The views expressed do not  necessarily reflect the views of LES or Finnegan.</em></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 13:23:56 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Implementers of Standard Essential Patents in Germany Must “Clearly and Unambiguously” Express </title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=526275</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=526275</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h2>Implementers of Standard Essential  Patents in Germany Must “Clearly and Unambiguously” Express Their Willingness to  Take a License Under Fair, Reasonable, and Non-Discriminatory Terms</h2>
<p><strong>By </strong><a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/johnpaul/">John Paul</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/briankacedon/">Brian Kacedon</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/en/professionals/anthony-d-del-monaco.html">Anthony D. Del Monaco</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/ceciliasanabria/">Cecilia Sanabria</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/en/professionals/umber-aggarwal.html">Umber Aggarwal</a></p>
<p><strong>Edited</strong> by <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/johnpaul/">John Paul</a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/briankacedon/">Brian Kacedon</a>, <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/en/professionals/anthony-d-del-monaco.html">Anthony D. Del Monaco</a>, and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.finnegan.com/ceciliasanabria/">Cecilia Sanabria</a><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Abstract: Germany’s  highest court clarified the obligations of owners of standard essential patents  (SEPs) when licensing their patents. They are not always required to submit  claim charts to alleged infringers to satisfy their notice obligation and can  offer less favorable terms than previous licenses if circumstances with the  accused infringers are different from those with previous licensees. They may  also insist on a license that includes all patents infringed by the implementer  and a worldwide portfolio license if the alleged infringer develops or  manufactures the accused products in different geographical regions. Also, to  preserve a Fair, Reasonable, and Non-Discriminatory (“FRAND”) defense, accused infringers must declare  their willingness to agree to a license on FRAND terms “clearly and  unequivocally,” and if no agreement between the parties is reached, the accused  infringers must diligently provide information on alleged infringing use and an  appropriate amount of security based on such use.</p>
<p><strong>What Does SEP and FRAND Mean?</strong><br>
  Standard setting organizations are industry  groups that collaborate to make standards on technology enabling different  entities to make different products that can work together in the same way.  Different examples of technology covered by standards include USB and Bluetooth. </p>
<p> If a patent claims the technology required to  practice the standard, that patent may be considered a standard essential  patent (SEP). If a patent is designated as standard essential, the SEP owner typically  must agree to license the SEP using fair, reasonable, and non‑discriminatory (FRAND)  terms to help promulgate the technology. If the SEP owner does not offer a  license under FRAND terms, an alleged infringer may claim a defense that it  should not have to execute a license to practice the standard due to the  unreasonable terms the SEP owner imposed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>
  <strong>Background of the Case</strong> <br>
  Sisvel  accused Haier of infringing a SEP. Nearly a year later, Haier responded by requesting  more information. And at a later date, Haier said it was willing to take a  license if a German court found Haier infringed a valid patent.</p>
<p> The  parties rejected each other’s license offers, and Sisvel sued Haier for patent  infringement at the Regional Court of  Düsseldorf. Haier invoked a FRAND defense based on Sisvel offering much higher  license fees to Haier than it did to a previous licensee. </p>
<p> In  2015, the Court of Justice of the European Union, in <em>Huawei v. ZTE</em>,  created a five‑step framework that governs enforcement of SEPs in all European  Union countries. The framework establishes a series of obligations the SEP  owner must meet to seek an injunction based on SEPs and obligations that the accused  SEP infringer must meet to invoke the FRAND defense against the SEP owner’s  injunctive relief claim: </p>
<p> Step  1: To enforce a SEP, the SEP owner must give notice of infringement. <br>
  Step  2: The accused infringer must then express its willingness to agree to a  licensee agreement on FRAND terms. <br>
  Step  3: The SEP owner must offer a license on FRAND terms. <br>
  Step  4: The accused SEP infringer must respond diligently. If it does not accept the  offer, it must present a counteroffer on FRAND terms. <br>
  Step  5: If the counteroffer is rejected, the accused infringer must provide  information on their use and provide appropriate security calculated based on  the provided information.</p>
<p> In <em>Sisvel,</em> the German Federal Court of Justice, the country’s  highest court, further clarified how this framework is applied in German  courts.</p>
<p> <strong>The Decisions of the Lower Court  and Appeals Court</strong><br>
  After  determining that Haier infringed the patents, the Regional Court of Düsseldorf  rejected Haier’s FRAND defense and granted Sisvel’s injunction, concluding that  Haier failed to provide information on alleged infringing use and provide appropriate  security after Haier’s counteroffer was rejected (steps 5 and 6). That court  held that it was irrelevant whether Sisvel’s offers complied with FRAND because  Haier still failed its obligations. </p>
<p> On appeal, the Higher Regional Court  of Düsseldorf reversed, finding that Haier’s FRAND defense had merit. It  disagreed with the lower court’s decision to not assess whether Sisvel’s  license proposals were FRAND-compliant (step 3). In performing this analysis,  the appellate court held that Sisvel’s offers were discriminatory since it  offered Hisense, one of Haier’s competitors, a significantly lower royalty rate  (80% less) without providing a reasonable and objective explanation for this  disproportionate treatment. The appeals court ruling interpreted the <em>Huawei </em>framework consecutively — finding  that the obligations of a certain step of the negotiation process only applied when  the obligations of the previous steps were adequately completed. In the view of  the appeals court, Sisvel never satisfied its obligation to offer a  FRAND-compliant license offer (step 3) so Haier was never obligated to provide information and security (step 5).</p>
<p> <strong>The Decision by the German Federal  Court of Justice</strong><br>
  The  German Federal Court of Justice reversed the appeals court, finding that Haier failed  its obligations at an earlier stage in the negotiations because it delayed  negotiations and did not clearly express a willingness to take a license with  FRAND terms (step 2). Specifically, the high court found that Haier merely  presented an initial “hope” to have formal negotiations and, in later  correspondence, only showed a conditional willingness to take a license on  FRAND terms if a German court found the patent claims valid and that Haier  infringed those patent claims.</p>
<p> The  high court also found that patent owners do not need to submit claim charts to  satisfy their notice requirement, so Sisvel’s identification of the SEP and  Haier’s alleged infringement was sufficient to meet Sisvel’s initial  obligations (step 1).</p>
<p> The  high court also reversed the appeals court’s holding that Sisvel offered a  license with discriminatory terms because the appeals court did not consider the  fact that the Chinese government placed political pressure on Sisvel to give  Hisense a lower royalty rate. This fact made the circumstances of Hisense and  Haier different and justified Sisvel offering different license terms for  Hisense and Haier.</p>
<p> The  high court commented on three other aspects of SEP licensing:</p>
<ul>
  <li>A  SEP owner may require a license to cover all SEPs implemented in the infringing  products. </li>
  <li>A  SEP owner may require a worldwide license if a potential licensee that only  develops products for a specific geography is not disadvantaged. For example,  if an alleged infringer does not manufacture or distribute a product in a  certain geographical area, then the SEP owner cannot require the alleged  infringer to pay licensing fees for patents in the worldwide portfolio that  cover that geographical area.</li>
  <li>A  SEP owner’s claim for damages involving SEP licensing issues can exceed the  amount of the expected FRAND license fee. In other words, a non-compliant  licensee’s liability is not limited to the standard fair and reasonable  royalty.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Strategy and Conclusion</strong> <br>
  <a>In Germany, SEP owners have certain rights and obligations when  licensing their patents: </a></p>
<p><a>(1) They must give notice of infringement but do not necessarily  have to submit claim charts to infringers to satisfy this notice obligation.</a><br>
  (2) They must offer FRAND terms  but they can offer less favorable terms than previous licenses if circumstances  with the accused infringer are different from those with previous licensees. <br>
  (3) They may insist the license  include all patents infringed by the implementor. <br>
(4) They may further insist on worldwide  portfolio licenses for patents the implementor needs for the legal manufacturer  or legal distribution in various geographical locations the implementor  operates in.</p>
<p> Furthermore, to preserve a FRAND  defense, accused infringers must declare their willingness to agree to a  licensee on FRAND terms “clearly and unequivocally.” If no agreement between  the parties is reached, accused infringers must diligently provide information on alleged infringing use  and appropriate amount of security based on such use. </p>
<p> The <em>Sisvel </em>decision can be found <a target="_blank" href="https://www.finnegan.com/images/content/3/1/v2/311102/Sisvel-v-Haier.pdf">here</a>.<strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Editors and Authors</strong><br>
  The editors and authors are  attorneys at Finnegan, Henderson, Farabow, Garrett &amp; Dunner, LLP.</p>
<p><em>This  article is for informational purposes and does not constitute legal advice.</em><br>
<em>The views expressed do not  necessarily reflect the views of LES or Finnegan.</em></p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 01:28:40 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Recent U.S. Decisions Affecting Licensing</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=305745</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=305745</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Purchaser of Patents Barred from Asserting Patents Against Practicing Entity Led to Believe it Would Not Be Sued by Prior Owner</h1>
<p><em>By John Paul, Brian Kacedon, and Hala Mourad<br>
</em><br>
High Point purchased patents relating to CDMA communications network technology from Avaya, a spin-off of Lucent Technologies, which spun off of AT&amp;T. Within three days of acquiring the patents, High Point began sending demand letters asserting infringement, including to Sprint and its corporate affiliates. Sprint had worked with Lucent and AT&amp;T to build a communications network for years through licensed and unlicensed activity.&nbsp;<br>
High Point filed a patent infringement suit against Sprint, accusing Sprint of violating licensing agreements entered into with High Point’s predecessors and alleging that Sprint’s network operated through a combination of licensed and unlicensed equipment in an infringing manner. The United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit affirmed the district court’s determination that High Point’s lawsuit was barred by equitable estoppel, a doctrine in patent law that bars a patentee’s lawsuit where it would be unfair to allow the lawsuit to proceed. The Federal Circuit agreed.<br>
<br>
<strong>Background</strong><br>
In the early 1990s, AT&amp;T’s Bell Labs (“AT&amp;T”) developed patents relating to standards for CDMA communications networks around the world. AT&amp;T spun off and assigned the patents to Lucent Technologies (“Lucent”), and Lucent spun off and assigned the patents to Avaya, Inc. (“Avaya”).&nbsp;<br>
<br>
Around 1995, Sprint Nextel Corp. (“Sprint”) decided to build a nationwide CDMA network. To do so, Sprint contracted with Nortel, Motorola, and other vendors to supply equipment for the network. In 1996 and 1997, Sprint executed supply agreements with Nortel and Motorola, respectively, for equipment for the CDMA infrastructure.&nbsp;<br>
<br>
In 1996 and 1999, AT&amp;T (and later Lucent) also agreed to supply Sprint with equipment. The supply agreements with AT&amp;T and Lucent included limited licenses for several patents, including the patents that High Point ultimately purchased from Avaya. Later, Sprint signed a Memorandum of Understanding with Lucent to develop multi-vendor interoperability within Sprint’s CDMA network. That same year, Lucent entered a similar licensing arrangement with Nortel, which was later cross-licensed to Sprint. Avaya did not discuss licensing the patents after Lucent assigned them.&nbsp;<br>
<br>
Initially, the zones in Sprint’s network were covered by a patent license, either by the license in the Lucent-Sprint supply agreement, or by a cross-license that originated from an agreement with Lucent and Nortel (which applied to Sprint’s use of Nortel equipment). But as the network grew, Sprint began to purchase and use unlicensed equipment.&nbsp;<br>
In March 2008, Avaya sold the CDMA patents to High Point. Within three days of acquiring the CDMA patents, High Point began sending demand letters asserting infringement, including to Sprint and its affiliates. High Point filed a patent infringement suit against Sprint for violating its licensing agreements and infringing its CDMA patents.&nbsp;<br>
<br>
A Kansas district court entered summary judgment in favor of Sprint, finding that Sprint suffered economic and evidentiary prejudice because Lucent and Avaya remained silent as to any patent rights while Sprint actively tried to establish its CDMA network through the sale, purchase, and licensing of network equipment. High Point appealed.<br>
<br>
<strong>The High Point Decision</strong><br>
Sprint and the other defendants argued that High Point’s predecessors, including AT&amp;T, Lucent, and Avaya, communicated through their actions and silence that Sprint would not be disturbed in establishing a CDMA network with equipment from multiple vendors. They also argued that High Point’s predecessors could have sued much earlier, but chose not to. Instead of suing, High Point’s predecessors expressly agreed to help Sprint integrate the equipment from other vendors. The defendants argued they relied on the conduct of High Point’s predecessors in investing in interoperable CDMA infrastructure and foregoing the pursuit of non-infringing alternatives, and would now be prejudiced economically if High Point was permitted to continue with the suit.&nbsp;<br>
<br>
High Point argued that preventing it from asserting the CDMA patents because the previous patent owners failed to do so for several years is an extraordinary remedy that should not apply without a statement of intent not to do so given the complexity of the business transactions involved and the sophistication of the parties. High Point also argued that under the various licensing agreements, it was prevented from asserting infringement until more recently.&nbsp;<br>
<br>
The Federal Circuit held that that the district court ruled appropriately to preclude High Point from prosecuting its lawsuit against the defendants. The court first outlined the three elements required to establish whether High Point’s lawsuit should be barred by equitable estoppel: (1) the patentee, through misleading conduct (or silence), leads the alleged infringer to reasonably infer that the patentee does not intend to enforce its patent against the alleged infringer; (2) the alleged infringer relies on that conduct; and (3) the alleged infringer will be materially prejudiced if the patentee is allowed to proceed with its claim.<br>
The Federal Circuit concluded that the misleading conduct of High Point’s predecessors caused Sprint to reasonably infer that they would not assert the CDMA patents while Sprint purchased unlicensed equipment to build its network. The court noted that the conduct of High Point’s predecessors included both silence and active conduct. The court noted that High Point’s predecessors repeatedly did nothing to assert their patent rights when the patent licenses were not in effect. The court also dismissed High Point’s argument that bad faith must be present to establish intent, particularly in view of the active participation of High Point’s predecessors in building Sprint’s CDMA network. The Federal Circuit also agreed with the district court’s determination that the defendants detrimentally relied on the conduct of High Point’s predecessors and that the defendants were prejudiced by the delay.<br>
<br>
Accordingly, the Federal Circuit affirmed the district court’s ruling.&nbsp;<br>
<br>
<strong>Strategy and Conclusion</strong><br>
This case illustrates how the relationships and course of conduct between prior owners of patents and practicing entities can affect the ability of a subsequent owner to assert the patents against those practicing entities, and how it can be difficult for purchasers of patents to know and evaluate how their rights to assert the patents against practicing entities are affected by such relationships and course of conduct between the prior owners and those entities against which the patents may be asserted.<br>
<br>
<strong>Further Information</strong><br>
The High Point opinion can be found here.&nbsp;<br>
<br>
<strong>Editors and Authors</strong><br>
The editors and authors are attorneys at Finnegan, Henderson, Farabow, Garrett &amp; Dunner, LLP.</p>
<p><span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>John Paul<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>john.paul@finnegan.com<br>
<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>Brian Kacedon<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>brian.kacedon@finnegan.com<br>
<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>Robert Wells<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>robert.wells@finnegan.com<br>
<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>Robert MacKichan<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>robert.mackichan@finnegan.com<br>
<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>Hala Mourad<span class="Apple-tab-span"> </span>hala.mourad@finnegan.com<br>
<br>
<em>This article is for informational purposes and does not constitute legal advice.<br>
The views expressed do not necessarily reflect the views of LES or Finnegan.</em></p>
<div></div>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 17:30:49 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Linux Foundation Open Compliance Program Is Providing Resources for Licensing Professionals</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=293866</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=293866</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>The Linux Foundation Open Compliance Program Is Providing Compliance Resources for Licensing Professionals</h1>
<em>By Karen Copenhaver, Choate, Hall &amp; Stewart LLP, Counsel to the Linux Foundation<br>
</em><br>
Linux and open source software now provide fundamental infrastructure for many of the worlds’ most successful industries and are being used to build the most innovative technologies of our time. &nbsp;Open source license compliance must be a focus for licensing professionals who work on transactions involving the creation, distribution, and use of such technologies. &nbsp;To address compliance concerns, as well as other important matters such as data security, it is necessary to understand the security and nature of the open source components included in software packages that are routinely delivered throughout the supply chain. &nbsp;Accordingly, preparing licensing professionals to tackle these challenges efficiently is critical to ensuring their clients are positioned to realize the benefits of the rapid innovation cycles and cost reductions of Linux and open source software.<br>
<br>
In recognition of the foregoing, and their common dependency on these essential technology building blocks, companies have come together as part of the Linux Foundation Open Compliance Program to collaborate on the continuing evolution of efficient practices for handling ever more complex data regarding the packages in use. &nbsp;In particular, the Software Package Data Exchange (SPDX®) and the OpenChain Workgroups are establishing and automating best practices to ease open source compliance for companies and developers.<br>
<br>
The SPDX specification is a standard format for capturing and communicating the components, licenses and copyrights associated with a software package for use internally and across a supply chain. &nbsp;The SPDX specification is developed by the SPDX Workgroup which includes representatives from more than 20 organizations—software, systems and tool vendors, foundations and systems integrators—all working to realize the benefits of a standardized format for gathering and sharing software package data. &nbsp;For example, with SPDX 2.0 a device manufacturer can easily understand what open source software has been used to build the device components, what versions of that software are being used, what modules have been integrated, and how this information may have changed from release to release. This allows companies to more efficiently identify and understand open source compliance obligations or vulnerabilities and address them before shipment.<br>
<br>
The SPDX Workgroup recently announced the release of version 2.0 of its specification, which includes a human and machine-readable view of layered license dependencies that will make exchange of open source software components and license data even more useful and accurate. &nbsp;The relationship view of license dependencies is made possible through new features that include a deeper level of description and context in files and packages, including those external to the SPDX specification. &nbsp;This helps to create taxonomy for modules that can be used not only for compliance but also for identifying files that may require updating to address potential security vulnerabilities. &nbsp;Other new features include the ability to relate SPDX documents to each other, making the SPDX format valuable for a broader range of internal and external uses.<br>
<br>
The OpenChain Workgroup is a community effort to standardize common best practices for open source software management to enable efficient and effective compliance with open source licenses. &nbsp;It is intended to both improve the performance of all participants in the supply chain, where many compliance failures originate, and to reduce costs by avoiding duplication of efforts. &nbsp;The OpenChain Workgroup’s output will be a baseline process that can be customized as companies and developers see fit. &nbsp;OpenChain will start by leveraging existing best practices in the Linux ecosystem, such as Debian, to provide an initial set of guidelines intended to be used as a basis for monitoring and developing compliance programs. &nbsp;Having a standard approach to compliance processes will benefit both suppliers and their customers. &nbsp;Suppliers have been slow to implement processes due to the confusing and conflicting requirements received from their various customers. &nbsp;A consistent approach and set of requirements reduces that friction and will relieve the burden on both suppliers and customers of conducting repetitive audits by enabling a single third party audit to be conducted in accordance with the common standards. &nbsp;Founding members of the OpenChain Workgroup include ARM, Qualcomm, Samsung, SanDisk and Wind River.<br>
<br>
To learn more about SPDX and participate, please visit: <a href="http://spdx.org">http://spdx.org</a><br>
<br>
To learn more about the OpenChain Workgroup and to participate in early discussions, please visit: <a href="https://wiki.linuxfoundation.org/openchain/start">https://wiki.linuxfoundation.org/openchain/start</a><br>
<br>
The Linux Foundation supports the world's top developers and companies to build ecosystems that accelerate open technology development and commercial adoption. Together with the worldwide open source community, it is solving the hardest technology problems by creating the largest shared technology investment in history. Founded in 2000, The Linux Foundation today provides tools, training and events to scale any open source project, which together deliver an economic impact not achievable by any one company.]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 16:41:54 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Digital Content: How it&apos;s Being Created, Exploited, Licensed and Protected Online</title>
<link>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=275121</link>
<guid>https://members.lesusacanada.org/news/news.asp?id=275121</guid>
<description><![CDATA[<h1>Digital Content: How it's Being Created, Exploited, Licensed and Protected Online</h1>
<p>Few high tech developments have impacted our personal and professional operations over the past decade more than digitalization of content. From music and photos to business files and banking, plenty of questions continue to arise about overall management of digital content.</p>
<p>Experts in the field recently participated in an interactive panel discussion at the Licensing Executives (U.S.A. and Canada) Winter Meeting in Silicon Valley to provide perspective on the issue. The panel was moderated by Dave Green of Microsoft, who was joined by panelists Jeff Jampol of JAM Inc., Kelly Jo MacArthur of the MacArthur Group LLC., David Reeder, Vice President, GREENLIGHT, and Lisa Oratz of Perkins Coie.</p>
<p>Jeff Jampol of JAM, Inc. which manages artists like the Doors and Janis Joplin, kicked off the lively discussion by noting a few fundamental shifts in media creation over the past decade: creative content, both personal and professional, are now stored and accessible primarily in the form of digital content. Creations, work documents, movies, songs, photos and games - the very essence of our lives exists in a medium that only requires copying and distribution to be enjoyed. </p>
<p>However, as Mr. Jampol quickly pointed out that just because the creative content is easy to access and use does not in itself reduce such media to a commodity. Managing these creations is different than licensing technology or software.&nbsp; "We're not talking about widgets here. These artists aren't just artists - they're vendors and brands.&nbsp; And it's our job to be their brand managers," he said.</p>
<p>But with YouTube, FaceBook and the plethora of other ways to connect with consumers directly, what's a licensor and brand manager to do?&nbsp; How do they control the ease of access to this content, or should they control it? Are rights owners now throwing in the towel on rights?&nbsp; </p>
<p>The short answer is no.&nbsp; They're not giving up on rights, but there is a need to change the game.&nbsp; Some catching up is required in this area where the law in lagging significantly behind where technology and consumers are, and even further behind where they're headed. The panelists agreed that convenience is the name of the game, and things are moving faster than ever before. Moderator Dave Green noted that consumers are demanding that their favorite content be available how they want to experience, and not merely how the rights owners think it should be distributed. </p>
<p>And while consumers and their needs produce a rapidly changing environment, David Reeder articulated a simple philosophy that hasn't changed, even if the delivery methods have: there is still a radical disconnect between the value that owners ascribe to their works, and what consumers perceive.&nbsp; And the value proposition for intermediaries: labels, studios, managers, is being even further muddled as artists connect directly with fans. It seems both sides are empowered to interact directly with no agreements and no traditional brand protections.&nbsp; </p>
<p>Consumers and artists are taking advantage of these opportunities to engage each other, and this empowerment is changing business models and challenging the status quo.&nbsp; Record companies were highlighted as an example of an industry struggling to stay relevant.&nbsp; They've been left behind as new business models have been created to work around the establishment they've worked so hard to build. A key example is how consumers have shifted from having to own content to now simply having access to it.&nbsp;&nbsp; People seem far less interested in owning CDs and DVDs than they are in having access to the wide world of entertainment whenever and wherever they are.&nbsp; And the possibilities around monetizing access are huge for those who can (and want to) adapt.&nbsp; Apps were highlighted as an example of how those willing to embrace the change can pioneer new licensing models, even as pricing models come down.&nbsp; </p>
<p>As the panel put bets on the next big thing, it was obvious that subscription models are at the top of the list -- but subscriptions with intelligence.&nbsp; How can you sort through the millions of options out there?&nbsp; As consumers try to wade through everything available to them, filters may be the wave of the future.&nbsp; Finding what we want and accessing it how we want will likely shape the next wave of developments in digital content.&nbsp; Kelly Jo MacArthur pointed out that we're already seeing the beginning of this with different data plans for mobiles asking how much one wants to pay for how much access?&nbsp; Along with access, the amount of information consumers are willing to share about themselves and their preferences will shape the next wave of developments. </p>
<p>To read summaries on other high tech panels from the LES (USA &amp; Canada) Winter Meeting, visit <a href="http://www.lesusacanada.org">www.lesusacanada.org</a>. </p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
